<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>“Workplace Violence” on 911Cellular</title>
    <link>/tag/workplace-violence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in “Workplace Violence” on 911Cellular</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tag/workplace-violence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Real Estate Agents Can Stay Safe with Modern Safety Tools</title>
      <link>/blog/real-estate-agents-stay-safe-modern-safety-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/real-estate-agents-stay-safe-modern-safety-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Real estate agents operate in a dynamic and often unpredictable environment, putting them at risk when meeting strangers in unfamiliar settings. With the thrill of showcasing properties comes the critical need for heightened awareness and proactive strategies to combat workplace violence. Thankfully, today&amp;rsquo;s agents can tap into various innovative safety tools designed to boost personal security and reduce potential threats. By prioritizing safety, real estate professionals protect themselves and create a more secure experience for their clients. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore how embracing these modern solutions can transform how agents navigate their day-to-day challenges!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workplace Violence Awareness: How Wearables and AI Are Shaping Worker Safety</title>
      <link>/blog/workplace-violence-awareness-wearables-and-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/workplace-violence-awareness-wearables-and-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s ever-evolving workplace, safety and security are critical concerns. While wearable panic buttons initially gained popularity in healthcare settings and are now seeing increased use in educational environments, they are also becoming indispensable tools for manufacturers, government buildings, banks and office-based businesses. Artificial intelligence (AI) is also gaining popularity in security as it allows organizations to predict and detect emerging threats much faster, with improved accuracy. Together, these emerging technologies are absolutely transforming how organizations approach safety, preventing workplace violence and ensuring employee well-being.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
