<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The complete critical incident management platform on 911Cellular</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The complete critical incident management platform on 911Cellular</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 15:08:15 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Panic Button Systems for Modern Security Environments</title>
      <link>/panic-button-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 15:08:15 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>/panic-button-system/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New in 2025: Amplify Awareness About Your Safety Solutions with Our Curated Promotional Storefront!</title>
      <link>/blog/promotional-storefront-for-safety-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/promotional-storefront-for-safety-solutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At 911Cellular, we&amp;rsquo;re not just about cutting-edge safety and emergency communication solutions—we&amp;rsquo;re all about transforming your sense of security! We believe that true safety stems from awareness, preparedness and accessibility. That&amp;rsquo;s why we&amp;rsquo;re thrilled to unveil our exclusive promotional storefront, now available to our valued clients! Dive into a curated range of promotional products designed to empower your community and keep everyone safe and connected like never before! Get ready to elevate your safety game!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of School Safety in Texas: Integrating Cutting-Edge Technology with Comprehensive Risk Management</title>
      <link>/blog/integrating-cutting-edge-technology-with-comprehensive-risk-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/integrating-cutting-edge-technology-with-comprehensive-risk-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The safety of students and staff has always been a fundamental principle of education. As threats to school security continue to rise both in frequency and severity, many institutions nationwide are turning their attention to innovative ways to ensure they can proactively detect emerging threats to protect their students and staff from potentially life-threatening critical incidents. In the Lamar Consolidated Independent School District (LCISD) in Texas, the installation of advanced concealed weapons detection systems, complete with AI-powered evasion detection, is making waves. This cutting-edge initiative aims to thwart potential tragedies before they occur and paves the way for advanced, comprehensive risk management strategies on campus across the globe. With these innovative measures, schools are taking significant strides towards creating a safer environment for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>California&#39;s $10 Billion School Bond Passes: A Game-Changer for School Infrastructure and Safety</title>
      <link>/blog/california-proposition-2-school-safety-upgrades/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/california-proposition-2-school-safety-upgrades/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In November, California voters passed a groundbreaking $10 billion K-12 school construction bond to reshape the state&amp;rsquo;s educational infrastructure and elevate safety standards. With growing concerns about school safety, this bond presents a pivotal opportunity for schools to invest in critical upgrades, including advanced crisis management solutions such as emergency communication systems and panic buttons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tools to Help Maintain Hospital Operations During Severe Winter Weather</title>
      <link>/blog/tools-to-help-maintain-hospital-operations-during-severe-winter-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/tools-to-help-maintain-hospital-operations-during-severe-winter-weather/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When severe winter weather strikes, hospitals face unique challenges that can disrupt critical operations. From icy roads delaying staff commutes to power outages affecting life-saving equipment, the stakes are high. An effective emergency notification system and safety app can make the difference between chaos and continuity. Here’s how these technologies can enhance employee safety and keep hospitals running smoothly when winter weather hits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Real Estate Agents Can Stay Safe with Modern Safety Tools</title>
      <link>/blog/real-estate-agents-stay-safe-modern-safety-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/real-estate-agents-stay-safe-modern-safety-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Real estate agents operate in a dynamic and often unpredictable environment, putting them at risk when meeting strangers in unfamiliar settings. With the thrill of showcasing properties comes the critical need for heightened awareness and proactive strategies to combat workplace violence. Thankfully, today&amp;rsquo;s agents can tap into various innovative safety tools designed to boost personal security and reduce potential threats. By prioritizing safety, real estate professionals protect themselves and create a more secure experience for their clients. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore how embracing these modern solutions can transform how agents navigate their day-to-day challenges!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workplace Violence Awareness: How Wearables and AI Are Shaping Worker Safety</title>
      <link>/blog/workplace-violence-awareness-wearables-and-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/workplace-violence-awareness-wearables-and-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s ever-evolving workplace, safety and security are critical concerns. While wearable panic buttons initially gained popularity in healthcare settings and are now seeing increased use in educational environments, they are also becoming indispensable tools for manufacturers, government buildings, banks and office-based businesses. Artificial intelligence (AI) is also gaining popularity in security as it allows organizations to predict and detect emerging threats much faster, with improved accuracy. Together, these emerging technologies are absolutely transforming how organizations approach safety, preventing workplace violence and ensuring employee well-being.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of AI in Predicting and Preventing Critical Incidents in Educational Institutions</title>
      <link>/blog/role-of-ai-in-critical-incident-prediction-and-prevention-for-educational-institutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/role-of-ai-in-critical-incident-prediction-and-prevention-for-educational-institutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As technology continues to evolve, artificial intelligence (AI) is transforming how educational institutions address safety concerns. AI-powered safety technology is revolutionizing &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/critical-incident-management/&#34;&gt;critical incident management&lt;/a&gt; by enhancing prediction, prevention and response strategies in schools, colleges and universities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Mass Notification Systems Keep Hospitals Operational During Severe Weather</title>
      <link>/blog/how-mass-notification-systems-keep-hospitals-operational-during-severe-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/how-mass-notification-systems-keep-hospitals-operational-during-severe-weather/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From hurricanes to blizzards, severe weather events can present significant challenges for hospital operations, jeopardizing patient care and compromising safety. To remain operational and provide critical and life-saving care during these challenging weather events, hospital administrators must implement a comprehensive critical incident strategy bolstered by mass notification systems. Mass notification systems help ensure uninterrupted operations, safeguard patients and staff and maintain effective communication in the face of logistical challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building an Inclusive Emergency Response Strategy</title>
      <link>/blog/building-an-inclusive-emergency-response-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/building-an-inclusive-emergency-response-strategy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Emergencies can occur without warning, but being prepared can make all the difference. Schools, colleges, universities and businesses must implement inclusive emergency response strategies that account for their communities&amp;rsquo; diverse needs. Organizations can create safer environments that ensure everyone is accounted for during a crisis by prioritizing inclusivity, leveraging modern technology and fostering a culture of preparedness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emergency Preparedness for the Hybrid Workplace</title>
      <link>/blog/emergency-preparedness-for-the-hybrid-workplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/emergency-preparedness-for-the-hybrid-workplace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The hybrid model has become the new norm in today&amp;rsquo;s rapidly evolving workplace landscape. While this approach combines the flexibility of remote work with the structure of in-office days, it also brings unique challenges - especially regarding emergency preparedness. Whether employees are at their desks in the office or working remotely, organizations must prioritize safety to ensure seamless responses to any crisis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hotel Panic Button Laws and Regulations: Protecting Hospitality Workers</title>
      <link>/blog/hotel-panic-button-laws-and-regulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/hotel-panic-button-laws-and-regulations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The hospitality industry focuses on creating safe and welcoming environments for guests, but it is equally essential to ensure the safety of workers behind the scenes. To address increasing safety concerns for both staff and guests, several states and cities across the U.S. are implementing laws requiring hotels to provide panic buttons. This measure is critical for safeguarding both employees and patrons.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-rise-in-popularity-of-panic-buttons-for-hospitality-staff&#34;&gt;The Rise in Popularity of Panic Buttons for Hospitality Staff&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Violence against hospitality workers has surged, with some studies indicating that more than 65% of female and 50% of male hospitality workers experience mistreatment (&lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1938965518761993&#34;&gt;Sherwyn and Wagner, 2018&lt;/a&gt;). The 5-Star Promise Initiative launched by the American Hotel &amp;amp; Lodging Association (AHLA) garnered even more attention for the issue. Among its various components aimed at enhancing hotel worker safety is the recommendation to equip staff with &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/products/wearable-panic-buttons/&#34;&gt;panic buttons&lt;/a&gt;, enabling them to quickly call for help in emergencies. In response, several states and local governments have started enacting variations of the 5-Star Promise Initiative.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emergency Communication Without Smartphones for K-12 Schools</title>
      <link>/blog/emergency-communication-without-smartphones-k-12-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/emergency-communication-without-smartphones-k-12-schools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Effective emergency communication in K-12 schools is vital for maintaining safety and ensuring swift incident response. However, many schools are implementing strict policies that limit smartphone usage to create distraction-free learning environments, combat bullying, and prevent cheating. While these policies are beneficial for education, they pose challenges during emergencies when cell phones may not be accessible. Additionally, many teachers do not keep their cell phones near when instructing classes and weather events or infrastructure issues can disrupt cellular networks, making it essential for schools to consider multi-channel communication options even when cell phones are permitted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective De-Escalation Strategies for Healthcare Workers: Maintaining Calm and Safety</title>
      <link>/blog/effective-de-escalation-strategies-for-healthcare-workers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/effective-de-escalation-strategies-for-healthcare-workers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Effective de-escalation strategies in healthcare settings are vital for ensuring patients&amp;rsquo; and staff&amp;rsquo;s safety and well-being. Tensions can arise quickly due to factors such as a patient&amp;rsquo;s anxiety, cognitive impairments or external stressors. De-escalation strategies provide healthcare professionals with the tools to manage these high-pressure situations and diffuse potentially volatile encounters with empathy and skill. Below, we will outline proven techniques that can help de-escalate tense situations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spark Alert Relay: Revolutionizing School Safety with Automation</title>
      <link>/blog/spark-alert-relay-school-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/spark-alert-relay-school-safety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Schools face unique safety challenges that require rapid, coordinated responses to mitigate harm to students and staff. With 911Cellular&amp;rsquo;s newest innovation, Spark Alert Relay, schools can automate critical safety responses that traditionally required manual intervention. With Spark, physical security measures like alarms, PA announcements and building lockdowns can be immediately activated upon receiving a panic signal, significantly reducing response time during an emergency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Your Incident Management System: Business Continuity and Incident Response Standards ISO 22301 and ISO 22320</title>
      <link>/blog/understanding-iso-22301-and-iso-22320/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/understanding-iso-22301-and-iso-22320/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For organizations with essential or significant operations, it is necessary to build a resilient infrastructure ready to face any disruption. The Business Continuity and Incident Response Standards ISO 22301 and ISO 22320 provide a fundamental framework for &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/critical-incident-management/&#34;&gt;Critical Incident Management (CIM)&lt;/a&gt;, including incident communication systems and business continuity. These internationally recognized standards guide organizations in developing, implementing and optimizing systems that effectively navigate disruptions - protecting operations and stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Your Incident Management System: Understanding Crisis and Emergency Risk Communication (CERC)</title>
      <link>/blog/understanding-crisis-and-emergency-risk-communication-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/understanding-crisis-and-emergency-risk-communication-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Created by the Centers for Disease Control (CDC), the Crisis and Emergency Risk Communication establishes a framework for effective communication during an emergency. The CERC framework is designed to help responders manage public expectations, build trust and encourage protective behaviors. This level of structured communication can significantly improve incident outcomes during situations involving uncertainty, fear or widespread impacts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Your Incident Management System: Understanding The National Incident Management System (NIMS)</title>
      <link>/blog/understanding-the-national-incident-management-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/understanding-the-national-incident-management-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being prepared with a structured critical incident management system can mean the difference between chaos and swift recovery. The National Incident Management System (NIMS), developed by FEMA, offers an effective, standardized and comprehensive approach to incident management that is flexible enough to fit a variety of sectors, organization sizes and incident types.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-benefits-of-nims-for-businesses&#34;&gt;Key Benefits of NIMS for Businesses&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unified, Efficient Response:&lt;/strong&gt; NIMS provides a universal framework and standardized language and procedures, enabling seamless collaboration with public safety agencies, first responders and other stakeholders during emergencies. This helps minimize response times and prevent escalation. For this reason, the U.S. Department of Education strongly encourages all k-12 and higher education institutions to incorporate NIMS into their critical incident plan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scalability and Flexibility:&lt;/strong&gt; The system adapts to any incident size or complexity, whether a minor internal issue or a large-scale emergency requiring external assistance.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comprehensive Planning:&lt;/strong&gt;  NIMS builds upon the Incident Command System to provide a comprehensive framework for critical incident management from prevention and mitigation to response and recovery.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview-and-building-blocks-of-nims&#34;&gt;Overview and Building Blocks of NIMS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NIMS is comprised of three key components - resource management, command and coordination and communications and information management. Regardless of how NIMS is scaled to fit your organization or incident, each of these building blocks is essential for a successful outcome.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>911Cellular Partners with Beacon Communications to Provide Advanced Critical Communication Solutions</title>
      <link>/blog/911cellular-beacon-communications-partnership/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/911cellular-beacon-communications-partnership/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a significant move to progress the critical communications industry, 911Cellular is thrilled to announce a new partnership with Beacon Communications, a leader in full-service critical communications for over 25 years. This collaboration unites 911Cellular’s cutting-edge panic button and mass notification systems technology with Beacon’s extensive portfolio of critical communication and business intelligence solutions. Together, we’re creating an unparalleled critical incident management solution for facilities where safety and efficiency are essential.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For decades, both 911Cellular and Beacon Communications have independently served the security needs of healthcare organizations, education institutions, private businesses, and government entities. By joining forces, we’re now uniquely positioned to deliver even more comprehensive and agile solutions that ensure timely responses to any crisis, an initiative that will continue to keep people safe for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Beacon Communications’ expertise in integrated communication technologies, combined with 911Cellular’s end-to-end panic button and mass notification tools, offers an essential, all-encompassing solution for any emergency scenario.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Your Incident Management System: Understanding the Incident Command System (ICS)</title>
      <link>/blog/understanding-the-incident-command-system-organizational-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/understanding-the-incident-command-system-organizational-structure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://training.fema.gov/emiweb/is/icsresource/assets/ics%20organizational%20structure%20and%20elements.pdf&#34;&gt;Incident Command System (ICS)&lt;/a&gt; is a standardized emergency management approach widely used across both public and private sectors. Initially developed by FEMA in response to natural disasters and large-scale emergencies, ICS provides a framework for coordinating resources, personnel and communications to manage incidents effectively. ICS is only used for incident management and does not guide incident preparation or recovery.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For businesses, adopting the ICS structure can help ensure a coordinated response during an emergency, reducing chaos and confusion. Here&amp;rsquo;s a breakdown of the key components that will help your organization integrate ICS into its incident management system (IMS).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Safe Learning Environments: How Lakewood, Ohio Schools&#39; RESET and Peer Mediation Programs Are Prioritizing Safety</title>
      <link>/blog/safe-learning-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/safe-learning-environments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;October is Ohio School Safety Month—a time to reflect on strategies that promote emotional and physical well-being, conflict resolution and safety through tools like &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/products/emergency-notification-system/&#34;&gt;emergency communication systems&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/products/wearable-panic-buttons/&#34;&gt;panic buttons&lt;/a&gt; in school settings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In honor of Ohio Schools Safety Month, we wanted to highlight Lakewood, Ohio School&amp;rsquo;s innovative RESET and Peer Mediation programs, which are creating safe learning environments by focusing on mental health, emotional regulation and conflict resolution. These programs go beyond traditional disciplinary methods, showing how schools can support students in becoming their best selves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critical Incident Debrief: Why Post-Incident Analysis is Crucial for Improvement</title>
      <link>/blog/why-post-incident-analysis-is-crucial-for-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/why-post-incident-analysis-is-crucial-for-improvement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Responding to critical incidents requires well-prepared plans and swift action. However, even the most comprehensive can encounter unforeseen challenges when put into practice. Making post-incident analysis an essential part of your critical incident management strategy. By conducting thorough reviews and debriefs after an incident, organizations can identify areas for improvement, strengthen their procedures and enhance their ability to handle future crises.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing Mental Health After Critical Incidents: Post-Traumatic Support Strategies</title>
      <link>/blog/managing-mental-health-after-critical-incidents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/managing-mental-health-after-critical-incidents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a critical incident, the immediate focus is often on physical safety and operational continuity. Yet, the psychological impact on employees, students or community members can have a profound, lasting effect. Addressing mental health is essential for recovery and resilience. For business owners, healthcare leaders, school administrators and management teams, understanding how to support the mental well-being of those affected is crucial. This guide provides insights and actionable advice to help organizations support the healing journey after critical incidents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Communication Breakdown in Business: How It Impacts Critical Incident Management and How to Address It</title>
      <link>/blog/communication-breakdown-in-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/communication-breakdown-in-business/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even with a well-developed Critical Incident Management (CIM) plan, organizations are not immune to communication breakdowns during a crisis. Amid a critical incident, smooth communication can mean the difference between effective management and a disorganized response.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A communication breakdown in business can disrupt even the best-laid plans, leading to delays, confusion, and increased risks. Understanding why these breakdowns occur and how to prevent them is essential for businesses aiming to maintain safety and efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crisis Communication in the Digital Age: How to Ensure Effective Messaging During Emergencies</title>
      <link>/blog/crisis-communication-in-the-digital-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/crisis-communication-in-the-digital-age/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced, interconnected world, crisis communication has become vital to any organization&amp;rsquo;s critical incident management strategy. From natural disasters to security threats, the ability to effectively communicate during a crisis can significantly impact the outcome and overall safety of those involved. But how can organizations ensure their crisis messaging is effective in the digital age?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To effectively communicate during an emergency, we must consider the evolution of crisis communication, the challenges and opportunities presented by social media, and use this&#xA;knowledge to develop a successful strategy for the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active Shooter Drills in School and on Campus: Why Preparedness Matters</title>
      <link>/blog/active-shooter-drills-why-preparedness-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/active-shooter-drills-why-preparedness-matters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/campus-safety/&#34;&gt;campus safety&lt;/a&gt; becomes an increasingly urgent issue, schools and universities prioritize proactive measures to protect students and staff. One of the most critical steps in emergency preparedness is the implementation of active shooter drills. These tests provide hands-on experience in responding to an active shooter situation and can make a significant difference when a real-life crisis occurs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-active-shooter-drills-are-essential&#34;&gt;Why Active Shooter Drills Are Essential&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Active shooter drills are designed to simulate real-life crisis scenarios, helping students, teachers and staff understand how to react quickly and efficiently. According to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nces.ed.gov/programs/coe/indicator/a01/violent-deaths-and-shootings&#34;&gt;National Center for Educational Statistics&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;ldquo;there were a total of 50 active shooter incidents at elementary and secondary schools and a total of 18 active shooter incidents at postsecondary institutions&amp;rdquo; between 2000 and 2022. Those incidents resulted in &amp;ldquo;328 casualties (131 killed and 197 wounded)&amp;rdquo; amongst elementary and secondary schools and &amp;ldquo;157 casualties (75 killed and 82 wounded)&amp;rdquo; in postsecondary institutions. In many of these situations, individuals on-site had to act before law enforcement could arrive, making emergency preparedness the difference between life and death.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Staying Connected When It Matters Most</title>
      <link>/blog/staying-connected-when-it-matters-most/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/staying-connected-when-it-matters-most/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At 911Cellular, we&amp;rsquo;ve always believed that strong connections are the foundation of safe communities. From our earliest days, we&amp;rsquo;ve been committed to building solutions that bridge the gap between people in need and first responders. Today, our new overview video highlights that mission—reinforcing the importance of connection, especially in moments of crisis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;video controls=&#34;&#34; preload=&#34;metadata&#34; poster=&#39;/images/home-v2/720p-thumbnail-911cellular-brand-overview-video-2024 copy.webp&#39; &gt;&#xD;&#xA;                    &lt;source type=&#34;video/mp4&#34; src=&#34;https://911cellular-bucket.s3.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/911Cellular+Brand+-+Overview+Video+-+2024.mp4&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;/video&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our journey has been one of growth and innovation. We&amp;rsquo;ve consistently expanded our products and product functionality to meet the diverse safety needs of &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/industries/k12schools/&#34;&gt;K-12 schools&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/industries/higher-education/&#34;&gt;college campuses&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/industries/healthcare/&#34;&gt;hospitals&lt;/a&gt; and businesses. We understand that today&amp;rsquo;s institutions face unprecedented challenges both in their physical and digital spaces. That&amp;rsquo;s why we&amp;rsquo;re committed to staying at the forefront of technology, offering mobile &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/products/mobile-safety-app/&#34;&gt;safety apps&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/products/wearable-panic-buttons/&#34;&gt;panic buttons&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/products/emergency-notification-system/&#34;&gt;critical incident management software&lt;/a&gt; that help schools and businesses protect their people, comply with regulations and respond quickly and discreetly in crucial moments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Rise of Wearable Panic Buttons in School Settings</title>
      <link>/blog/the-rise-of-wearable-panic-buttons-in-school-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/the-rise-of-wearable-panic-buttons-in-school-settings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the integration of technology into school safety protocols has taken on new dimensions, especially with the emergence of &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/products/wearable-panic-buttons/&#34;&gt;wearable panic buttons&lt;/a&gt;. These devices have gained significant traction, revolutionizing how educational environments handle emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a Culture of Safety: How Campuses Can Promote Security Awareness Year-Round</title>
      <link>/blog/how-campuses-can-promote-security-awareness-year-round/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/how-campuses-can-promote-security-awareness-year-round/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating a culture of safety on college and university campuses is about more than just installing security cameras and implementing emergency procedures. It&amp;rsquo;s about fostering a deep-rooted sense of security awareness among students, staff, and faculty year-round.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In celebration of National Campus Safety Awareness Month, we wanted to share some insights on how different marketing and public relations (PR) tactics can keep safety top-of-mind and encourage proactive behavior on college campuses. Here&amp;rsquo;s how your institution can build and sustain a safety culture through effective promotion strategies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New York’s “Retail Worker Safety Act”: A New Era for Workplace Violence Prevention</title>
      <link>/blog/retail-worker-safety-act-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/retail-worker-safety-act-requirements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New York has made a significant move to enhance retail worker safety by passing the Retail Worker Safety Act (S.8358C/A.8947C). This new law requires retail employers to develop and implement comprehensive programs aimed at preventing workplace violence. It addresses the growing concern over violence in retail environments. With new safety measures set to take effect in the coming years, this law highlights the importance of &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/keyboard-panic-buttons/&#34;&gt;panic buttons&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/blog/workplace-violence-a-comprehensive-guide&#34;&gt;workplace violence prevention&lt;/a&gt; policies, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/products/mobile-safety-app/&#34;&gt;mobile safety apps&lt;/a&gt; in safeguarding retail employees.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what retail employers need to know about the law and how it will impact workplace safety.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Clery Act Amendments are Shaping Campus Crime Reporting in 2024</title>
      <link>/blog/clery-act-amenments-campus-crime-reporting-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/clery-act-amenments-campus-crime-reporting-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.911cellular.com/blog/understanding-clery-act-reporting-requirements&#34;&gt;Clery Act&lt;/a&gt;, formally known as the Jeanne Clery Disclosure of Campus Security Policy and Campus Crime Statistics Act, has been a cornerstone of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/campus-safety/&#34;&gt;campus safety&lt;/a&gt; and crime reporting since its inception in 1990. In 2024, lawmakers adopted several key amendments, reflecting campus safety&amp;rsquo;s evolving challenges and complexities. These changes aim to enhance transparency, improve data collection methods and strengthen the accountability of educational institutions. Here&amp;rsquo;s how these amendments are shaping the landscape of campus crime reporting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Benefits of Integrating AI and IoT in Emergency Response</title>
      <link>/blog/the-benefits-of-integrating-ai-and-iot-in-emergency-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/the-benefits-of-integrating-ai-and-iot-in-emergency-response/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s rapidly evolving technological landscape, artificial intelligence (AI) and the Internet of Things (IoT) are transforming industries across the globe. One of the most impactful areas where these technologies are making a significant difference is in &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.911cellular.com/community-emergency-response-team-training&#34;&gt;emergency response&lt;/a&gt;. As organizations and municipalities seek to enhance their preparedness and response capabilities, integrating AI and IoT into their emergency response strategies has become essential. This blog explores the key benefits of leveraging AI and IoT to create more efficient, effective, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/products/mobile-safety-app/&#34;&gt;proactive emergency response&lt;/a&gt; systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Every College Needs a Campus Safety App</title>
      <link>/blog/why-every-college-needs-a-campus-safety-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/why-every-college-needs-a-campus-safety-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s world, ensuring the safety of students, faculty, and staff is a top priority for college campuses. With the increasing prevalence of campus incidents, from minor emergencies to critical situations, it&amp;rsquo;s essential for institutions to be equipped with the right tools to &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/industries/higher-education/&#34;&gt;protect their communities&lt;/a&gt;. One such tool that has proven to be indispensable is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/products/mobile-safety-app/&#34;&gt;campus safety app&lt;/a&gt;. This blog explores why every college should invest in a campus safety app and how it enhances overall &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/campus-safety/&#34;&gt;campus safety&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Alyssa&#39;s Law Enhances School Security Systems</title>
      <link>/blog/how-alyssas-law-enhances-school-security-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/how-alyssas-law-enhances-school-security-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an era where the safety of students is paramount, schools across the United States are increasingly focused on enhancing their security systems. One of the most significant legislative measures driving this change is &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/alyssas-law/&#34;&gt;Alyssa&amp;rsquo;s Law&lt;/a&gt;, which has been enacted in several states to improve emergency response times and ensure the &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/industries/k12schools/&#34;&gt;safety of students&lt;/a&gt; during critical incidents. But what exactly does Alyssa&amp;rsquo;s Law entail, and how does it enhance school security systems? This blog explores the impact of Alyssa&amp;rsquo;s Law on school security and what it means for schools striving to keep their students safe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Incident Command System (ICS): A Critical Tool for Crisis Management</title>
      <link>/blog/understanding-the-incident-command-system-ics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/understanding-the-incident-command-system-ics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced world, where unforeseen events can disrupt operations in an instant, businesses and organizations must be prepared to respond effectively to emergencies. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s a natural disaster, a security threat, or a critical incident within your organization, having a structured and efficient response plan is essential. This is where the &lt;strong&gt;Incident Command System (ICS)&lt;/strong&gt; comes into play.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Back to School Safety Tips Administrators Must Know</title>
      <link>/blog/back-to-school-safety-tips-administrators-must-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/back-to-school-safety-tips-administrators-must-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the back-to-school season approaches, school administrators across the country are preparing to welcome students, staff, and faculty back to campus. While academics are a top priority, the safety and security of everyone on school grounds should be at the forefront of planning. In an age where safety concerns are more pressing than ever, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to adopt a proactive approach that combines technology, policy, and community engagement. Here are actionable steps and technological solutions that can help ensure a secure and smooth start to the academic year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Connecticut Addresses Home Health Care Workers&#39; Safety with Public Act 24-19</title>
      <link>/blog/connecticut-home-health-care-workers-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/connecticut-home-health-care-workers-safety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This past May, the Connecticut state legislature and Governor Ned Lamont took the first steps towards addressing unsafe work environments for healthcare workers through &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cga.ct.gov/asp/cgabillstatus/cgabillstatus.asp?selBillType=Public&amp;#43;Act&amp;amp;which_year=2024&amp;amp;bill_num=19&#34;&gt;Public Act 24-19&lt;/a&gt;, also known as An Act Concerning the Health and Safety of Connecticut Residents. The legislation focuses on improving the health and safety of Connecticut&amp;rsquo;s vulnerable and underserved populations as well as the home health care workers who serve them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Creating the In-Home Safety Grant Program was vital to addressing concerns about increased violence against home health care workers. The program provides funds to home health providers for improved safety protocols.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Must-Have Features for Your Emergency Notification System</title>
      <link>/blog/features-for-your-emergency-notification-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/features-for-your-emergency-notification-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the essential features that can transform your emergency notification system from basic to indispensable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compliance Matters: Navigating OSHA Regulations in Manufacturing</title>
      <link>/blog/osha-regulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/osha-regulations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore the critical aspects of OSHA compliance to ensure safety and efficiency in the manufacturing industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empowering Students: The Benefits of Using Safety Resources on Campus</title>
      <link>/blog/student-safety-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/student-safety-resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore the advantages of utilizing safety resources on campus to empower students and enhance their overall well-being.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the Effectiveness of Emergency Management Software</title>
      <link>/blog/emergency-management-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/emergency-management-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the key factors in evaluating the effectiveness of emergency management software and how to optimize its performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updates on Alyssa&#39;s Law legislation in Oklahoma</title>
      <link>/blog/alyssas-law-oklahoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/alyssas-law-oklahoma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stay informed on the latest developments regarding Alyssa&amp;rsquo;s Law legislation in Oklahoma.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Best Practices for Effective Emergency Communication Systems</title>
      <link>/blog/emergency-communication-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/emergency-communication-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, we will explore the best practices for implementing emergency communication systems to ensure effective and timely responses during critical situations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wireless Panic Buttons: Enhancing Staff Protection in the Workplace</title>
      <link>/blog/wireless-panic-buttons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/wireless-panic-buttons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the benefits of utilizing wireless panic buttons for staff protection in a workplace setting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovative Technology in Hospital Security</title>
      <link>/blog/hospital-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/hospital-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore the latest advancements in technology designed to enhance security measures in hospital settings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Duress Buttons Are a Proven Security Measure For All Institutions</title>
      <link>/blog/duress-buttons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/duress-buttons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore the importance of duress buttons as a security measure in various institutions and their effectiveness in reducing violent incidents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Safety App Essentials: Unveiling Key Features</title>
      <link>/blog/safety-app-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/safety-app-features/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the must-have features of a safety app to keep you protected in any situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Office Panic Buttons for Effective Security</title>
      <link>/blog/office-panic-buttons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/office-panic-buttons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the importance of implementing panic buttons in office settings for enhanced staff security measures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empower Your Team: Wearable Panic Buttons for Employees</title>
      <link>/blog/wearable-panic-buttons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/wearable-panic-buttons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the benefits of equipping your team with wearable panic buttons to enhance safety and security in the workplace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Emergency Response Procedures for Quick Action</title>
      <link>/blog/community-emergency-response-team-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/community-emergency-response-team-training/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the essential skills and techniques for effective community emergency response team training.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preventing Violence in Healthcare Workplaces</title>
      <link>/blog/preventing-violence-in-healthcare-workplaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/preventing-violence-in-healthcare-workplaces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore strategies to create a safer environment for healthcare professionals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating an Effective Crisis Management Plan</title>
      <link>/blog/crisis-management-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/crisis-management-plan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced and chaotic work environment, having a well-thought-out crisis management plan is crucial for businesses to navigate through unexpected challenges and maintain their reputation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empowering School Safety: Alyssa&#39;s Law Explained</title>
      <link>/blog/alyssas-law-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/alyssas-law-explained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover how &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/alyssas-law/&#34;&gt;Alyssa&amp;rsquo;s Law&lt;/a&gt; is revolutionizing school safety measures and empowering educators, students, and parents alike.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastering the Hospital Incident Command System (HICS)</title>
      <link>/blog/hospital-incident-command-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/hospital-incident-command-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the key strategies for effectively implementing the Hospital Incident Command System (HICS) in healthcare settings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Panic Button Guide for Staff Members</title>
      <link>/blog/panic-button/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/panic-button/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover how panic buttons can enhance safety and security in the workplace with this comprehensive guide for staff members.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening Campus Safety Procedures</title>
      <link>/blog/campus-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/campus-safety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ensuring the safety of students, faculty, and staff on campus is a top priority for educational institutions. Implementing effective campus safety procedures is essential to create a secure learning environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing Safety: Emergency Notification Systems</title>
      <link>/blog/emergency-notification-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/emergency-notification-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, we will delve into the importance of emergency notification systems and how they can maximize safety in various settings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maximize Crisis Response with Software Solutions</title>
      <link>/blog/crisis-management-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/crisis-management-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover how crisis management software can help organizations effectively respond to emergencies and minimize the impact of crises.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing Critical Incidents: Strategies for Success</title>
      <link>/blog/managing-critical-incidents/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/managing-critical-incidents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover effective strategies for managing critical incidents and ensuring successful outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Business Continuity Planning: Ensuring Success in Times of Crisis</title>
      <link>/blog/business-continuity-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/business-continuity-planning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the importance of having a comprehensive business continuity plan in place to navigate through times of crisis and ensure the success of your business.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preventing Workplace Violence: A Comprehensive Guide</title>
      <link>/blog/workplace-violence-a-comprehensive-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/workplace-violence-a-comprehensive-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover effective strategies to prevent workplace violence and create a safe work environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preventing School Shootings: Effective Strategies for Safety</title>
      <link>/blog/how-to-prevent-school-shootings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/how-to-prevent-school-shootings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover effective strategies to prevent school shootings and ensure the safety of students and staff.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How a Mass Notification System Can Save Lives</title>
      <link>/blog/how-a-mass-notification-system-can-save-lives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/how-a-mass-notification-system-can-save-lives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the power and importance of a mass notification system in emergency situations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preventing Workplace Violence in Healthcare: Safety Measures for Healthcare Workers</title>
      <link>/blog/preventing-workplace-violence-in-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/preventing-workplace-violence-in-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how healthcare workers can protect themselves from workplace violence with these safety measures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ensuring School Safety: A Comprehensive Guide</title>
      <link>/blog/ensuring-school-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/ensuring-school-safety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover effective strategies and measures to ensure the safety of students and staff in schools.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workplace Violence Training: Essential Tips for a Safe Workplace</title>
      <link>/blog/workplace-violence-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/workplace-violence-training/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the importance of workplace violence training and learn essential tips to create a safe and secure work environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Organizational Resilience: Strategies for Success</title>
      <link>/blog/organizational-resilience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/organizational-resilience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover effective strategies to strengthen your organization&amp;rsquo;s resilience and overcome challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winter Safety Tips: Stay Warm and Safe</title>
      <link>/blog/winter-safety-tips-stay-warm-and-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/winter-safety-tips-stay-warm-and-safe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover essential winter safety tips to stay warm and safe in extremely cold weather.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Streamline Incident Management with Powerful Software</title>
      <link>/blog/streamline-incident-management-with-powerful-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/streamline-incident-management-with-powerful-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover how powerful software can revolutionize the way you handle incidents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stay Connected: The Importance of Emergency Communication Systems</title>
      <link>/blog/stay-connected-the-importance-of-emergency-communication-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/stay-connected-the-importance-of-emergency-communication-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the crucial role of emergency communication systems in keeping people safe during critical situations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Clery Act Reporting Requirements</title>
      <link>/blog/understanding-clery-act-reporting-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/understanding-clery-act-reporting-requirements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you aware of the Clery Act reporting requirements? Read this blog post to understand what it entails and how it affects your university.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Celebrate New Year Safely: A Guide</title>
      <link>/blog/how-to-celebrate-new-year-safely-a-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/how-to-celebrate-new-year-safely-a-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover essential tips and guidelines to ensure a safe and enjoyable New Year&amp;rsquo;s celebration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Addressing Privacy and Compliance Concerns in Emergency Communication</title>
      <link>/blog/privacy-compliance-emergency-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/privacy-compliance-emergency-communication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;addressing-privacy-and-compliance-concerns-in-emergency-communication&#34;&gt;Addressing Privacy and Compliance Concerns in Emergency Communication&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s rapidly evolving digital landscape, the need for effective emergency communication systems has never been more critical. Whether you are in healthcare, education, or any other industry, ensuring the safety and security of your employees, students, or patients is a top priority. However, as organizations adopt advanced technology solutions for emergency communication, they must also navigate the complex terrain of privacy and compliance regulations. In this blog post, we will explore the challenges and strategies for addressing privacy and compliance concerns in emergency communication.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crisis Management in K-12 Schools: Best Practices and Case Studies</title>
      <link>/blog/crisis-management-in-k-12-schools-best-practices-and-case-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/crisis-management-in-k-12-schools-best-practices-and-case-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s world, ensuring the safety and security of students and staff in K-12 schools is a top priority. Schools must be prepared to respond swiftly and effectively to a wide range of crises, from natural disasters to security threats. This calls for a comprehensive approach to crisis management, one that incorporates best practices and draws from real-life case studies. In this blog, we will explore the key elements of crisis management in K-12 schools and showcase some case studies that highlight successful strategies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Panic Buttons with Security Infrastructure in Hospitals</title>
      <link>/blog/integrating-panic-buttons-with-security-infrastructure-in-hospitals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/integrating-panic-buttons-with-security-infrastructure-in-hospitals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the fast-paced and high-stress environment of hospitals, every second counts when it comes to ensuring the safety and security of patients, staff, and visitors. With the increasing importance of emergency response in healthcare settings, integrating panic buttons with existing security infrastructure has become a pivotal step in creating a comprehensive and efficient safety net. In this blog, we will explore the benefits and strategies of seamlessly integrating panic buttons into the security framework of hospitals, ultimately enhancing emergency response and safeguarding lives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Staff Training for Optimal Response to Critical Incidents</title>
      <link>/blog/enhancing-staff-training-for-optimal-response-to-critical-incidents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/enhancing-staff-training-for-optimal-response-to-critical-incidents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to critical incident management, preparedness is the cornerstone of effective response. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s a healthcare facility, an educational institution, or any other B2B setting, the ability of staff members to respond swiftly and decisively during emergencies can make the difference between a manageable situation and a catastrophe. This is where staff training steps onto the stage as a vital component of a comprehensive critical incident management strategy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Campus Security: Mass Notification for Colleges &amp; Universities</title>
      <link>/blog/enhancing-campus-security-mass-notification-for-colleges-universities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/enhancing-campus-security-mass-notification-for-colleges-universities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In higher education, the pursuit of knowledge and personal growth is accompanied by a responsibility to ensure the safety and well-being of students, faculty, and staff. With the complex and dynamic nature of campus life, colleges and universities face unique security challenges that demand innovative solutions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mass notification systems have emerged as a crucial tool in enhancing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/industries/higher-education/&#34;&gt;campus security&lt;/a&gt;, enabling educational institutions to respond effectively to emergencies and ensure the safety of their communities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Addressing Workplace Violence in Healthcare: A Call for Safer Environments</title>
      <link>/blog/workplace-violence-in-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/workplace-violence-in-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the realm of healthcare, where compassion, healing, and patient care take center stage, one would hope that the workplace remains a safe and supportive environment for both healthcare professionals and patients. Unfortunately, workplace violence has become an alarming issue that continues to plague the healthcare industry. The rising incidents of verbal, physical, and emotional abuse pose significant threats to the well-being of healthcare workers, patient outcomes, and the overall quality of healthcare delivery. This blog post aims to shed light on the disturbing trend of workplace violence in healthcare and explore potential solutions to create safer and more secure working environments for all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The importance of CPR &amp; first aid training in the workplace</title>
      <link>/blog/importance-of-cpr-training-in-the-workplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/importance-of-cpr-training-in-the-workplace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is it worth it to have everyone in your company CPR and first aid certified?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The short answer is that it is well worth the time, money, and effort to ensure that all of your employees are certified in first aid and CPR, and that they &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cprologist.com/blog/how-often-to-renew-your-cpr-certification/#:~:text=Whether%20you%20have%20your%20CPR%20%28basic%20life%20saving%29%2C,certified%2C%20you%20need%20to%20keep%20it%20renewed%20continuously.&#34;&gt;renew their certifications&lt;/a&gt; every two years. Here are some of the top reasons to make it a priority for your company.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special Needs Students Emergency Preparedness on Campus</title>
      <link>/blog/special-needs-emergency-preparedness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/special-needs-emergency-preparedness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In unpredictable situations, how can leaders in schools protect their special needs students? Violent incidents in schools are terrifying for everyone, and that is no different for the students, teachers, and aides in special needs classrooms.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It may, however, be even more difficult to ensure the &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/student-safety&#34;&gt;safety of students&lt;/a&gt; who have a different perspective of the world, and who cope with difficulties in a variety of ways. What is the best way to communicate and handle emergencies with these students in a high-stress and potentially dangerous situation?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the role of your HR Department in Workplace Safety?</title>
      <link>/blog/hr-workplace-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/hr-workplace-safety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Does workplace safety fall under the duties of your HR department? If so, what role do they play in keeping employees safe?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The HR department in your company has a lot of different &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thebalancecareers.com/how-hr-provides-career-help-4125267&#34;&gt;responsibilities&lt;/a&gt;. Depending on the size of your company, there could be a multitude of different roles and tasks throughout this department as well. These tasks could include general employee management, assisting with scheduling, hiring and terminating employees, handling workplace issues and confrontations, and yes, even the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/workplace-violence/&#34;&gt;safety of your workplace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, what is their role in workplace safety?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>School Shooting in Uvalde, Texas</title>
      <link>/blog/school-shooting-uvalde-texas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/school-shooting-uvalde-texas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On May 24th, a gunman entered an elementary school in Uvalde, Texas with an AR-15 and a handgun. He then proceeded to kill 21 children and adults, while also critically injuring even more, making this the deadliest school shooting in the United States since the Sandy Hook Elementary School shooting in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our hearts go out to the victims, their families, and the local community in Uvalde.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gun Violence in Schools: Does it Cause Lasting Damage?</title>
      <link>/blog/school-gun-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/school-gun-violence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Does gun violence cause lasting physical and psychological damage to America’s youth? Even in recent years with the COVID-19 pandemic, there has been a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.psu.edu/news/research/story/us-gun-violence-increased-30-percent-during-covid-19-pandemic/&#34;&gt;significant increase&lt;/a&gt; in the amount of gun violence in American schools, according to researchers at Penn State. Besides the obvious immediate effects on schoolchildren, there may be some long-lasting damage to consider.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What long-term mental and physical effects can be expected in young students who have previously experienced a violent event in their schools?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Can Businesses Reopen Safely?</title>
      <link>/blog/reopen-safely/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/reopen-safely/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While still in the midst of the COVID-19 pandemic many organizations are already turning their thoughts, and worries, to an unclear future. How do we collectively restart a stalled economy? What steps will it take for businesses, community organizations, universities, etc. to reopen safely? Reopening processes will need to be different for each organization and is dependent on several factors …&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt; and the subsequent &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.multistate.us/pages/covid-19-policy-tracker&#34;&gt;rules and regulations put in place by each state&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Availability of resources&lt;/strong&gt; such as masks, gloves, testing kits, etc. Access to PPE will continue to be necessary to safeguard community members and prevent a resurgence of COVID-19 cases.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infection rate.&lt;/strong&gt; Knowing the number of COVID-19 cases within your organization is just as important as knowing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/index.html&#34;&gt;number of cases in surrounding areas and states&lt;/a&gt; (i.e infection potentiality).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No matter how each of these variables affect your organization, one thing is clear, emerging from this pandemic will take collaboration and clear communication on both an organizational and individual level to reopen safely. On an organizational level this means communicating protocol changes on a consistent basis. This will require that you stay abreast of evolving current state rules/guidelines and how they apply specifically to your organization. Synthesizing this information and providing it in an easily digestible and applicable way is key to solidifying adherence. Communicating protocol changes needs to occur over a wide range of communication platforms in order to reach all members of your audience. However, communicating to your audience is not enough. Collecting community feedback is an essential component to understanding and addressing community needs. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/products/emergency-notification-system/&#34;&gt;911Cellular’s Mass Notification System&lt;/a&gt; allows organizations to send out mass notifications via 10 different platforms (call, text, email, etc.). Organizations can also choose to include community survey questions and feedback boards with their with mass notifications. This makes it effortless to collect and understand community feedback.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Log4j statement</title>
      <link>/blog/log4j-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/log4j-statement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Log4J vulnerability news is sweeping the world, and since it was the best practice logging library within the second most popular programming languages in the world it is affecting nearly every company in some way shape or form.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m happy to announce that 911cellular has zero impact since Java is not our language of choice, it is not affecting any of our solutions. Given the large impact this has had on the Java community we’ve reevaluated all our logging frameworks to ensure that a similar exploit is not possible with our logging frameworks in other languages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assaulted at work? Here&#39;s what to expect from your employer</title>
      <link>/blog/workplace-violence-employee-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/workplace-violence-employee-rights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What are your workplace violence employee rights? Is that even a thing? To what extent does your employer protect you from violence at work? These questions are important to ask in a world where workplace violence is steadily increasing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each year, almost 60% of all workplace assaults in the nation occur in the healthcare industry. This setting is no stranger to violence on the job, with many nurses, caretakers and other staff members seeing it as just part of their duties. Unfortunately, this attitude leads to a lack of reporting and therefore the data on workplace violence is actually far less shocking than the real numbers would reveal. It is estimated that around 25% of all workplace violence incidents go unreported.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Healthcare isn’t the only industry where workplace violence exists though. In other industries, workplace violence is still a major concern, with homicides accounting for nearly 10% of all fatal occupational injuries in 2015 according to the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As an employee, what rights do you have to protect you against violence at your workplace? Is your employer liable if you are a victim of violence at work? These questions can be tough to navigate and the answers can seem unclear at times, but you should nonetheless know some of the basic laws and guidelines in your industry as it pertains to workplace violence prevention.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The next generation emergency response team is not what you think</title>
      <link>/blog/emergency-response-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/emergency-response-teams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A little while back we touched on the importance of emergency action planning and how every organization should have an emergency response plan (EAP) in place even if they are not required to do so. For every organization, an EAP is only as good as the people who can coordinate the response and carry out the plan in place. In most cases, these people are labelled as the emergency response team (ERT) members and are relied upon to deliver swift, calculated response during times of crisis (when others are often frantic).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As is always the case for emergency response, each organization’s plan is unique, and some institutions are required to have more thorough planning in place than others. That being said, there are guidelines and insights that can apply to all organizations as it regards to emergency response teams and how to make them more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) suggests that ERT members should be &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.osha.gov/sites/default/files/publications/factsheet-workplaceevergencies.pdf&#34;&gt;well trained in emergency response&lt;/a&gt;, know the organization’s specific emergency plan, and be physically capable of carrying out the proper emergency response duties assigned to them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The next generation emergency response team is not what you think</title>
      <link>/blog/employee-safety-active-shooters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/employee-safety-active-shooters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Employee safety, especially active shooter situations, was the topic of conversation at the American Society of Safety Professionals (ASSP) Safety 2018 conference recently held in San Antonio, Texas. During this forum attendees were able to hear from FBI agents, law enforcement professionals and other key groups with insight into some best practices to promote employee safety during an active shooter situation at the workplace.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The general tone of the forum was that prevention is not always possible. This has become an unfortunate reality; and that making plans to safeguard employee safety for the largest possible number of people is key to minimizing casualties.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critical announcements within enterprise communications</title>
      <link>/blog/enterprise-communications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/enterprise-communications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is enterprise communications? Simply put, it’s an industry built around fast, reliable communication tools with the purpose of informing community members of a large institution in a timely manner. Obviously, the individual communications sent can vary in priority level and also in how they’re sent. Some may require large-scale communication to the entire enterprise, while others are much more targeted and focused on work-efficiency. Enterprises that deploy these tools may use multiple solutions to get the job done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workplace violence prevention: 5 things to do today</title>
      <link>/blog/workplace-violence-prevention/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/workplace-violence-prevention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Workplace violence has become a major issue for many businesses and healthcare systems in the U.S. for decades. According to the Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA), almost 2 million U.S. workers report having been a victim of violence at work each year. This number is even more staggering when you consider that about 3 out of every 4 workplace violence incidents occur in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/industries/healthcare/&#34;&gt;healthcare&lt;/a&gt; or social services industries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to the Bureau of Labor Statistics, 20,790 workers in the private industry &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/niosh/topics/violence/fastfacts.html&#34;&gt;experienced trauma&lt;/a&gt; from nonfatal workplace violence in 2018. Of these workers, over 70% were female and 20% required a month or longer away from work to recover.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These jarring statistics should alone provide enough motivation for employers to commit to a non-violent workplace environment, but the data even shows that there are significant financial consequences of persistent workplace violence as well. In healthcare for instance, over 58 incidents occur annually per 10,000 workers with an average cost per incident of over $3,000. This means that annually, per 10,000 workers, healthcare systems are losing nearly $200,000.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Despite all this negativity, there are many things that your organization can do today to help prevent workplace violence incidents from occurring regularly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Run, Hide, Fight&#39;, is it always right?</title>
      <link>/blog/active-shooter-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/active-shooter-response/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Very few people want to think about the topic of active shooter response on a regular basis, and for those who do, it’s usually their job to be prepared. It’s a parent’s nightmare to think of the possibility of an active shooter situation at their children’s school, yet the number of school shooting incidents has been steadily increasing for several decades. It’s not just schools that have seen increased shooting events either, as the number of mass shootings in the United States hit an all-time high in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With all the chaos and confusion that transpires during these horrific events, it’s difficult for those involved to keep calm and remember how they were trained to respond (assuming they were trained at all). This is why training repetition is key. It’s far more likely for people to remember something they were exposed to over and over again.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’ve never learned about active shooter response before, now’s the time to get your first exposure to the topic. For everyone else, let this serve as a repeated learning session. Hopefully this will never have to be put into action, but it’s always best to prepare for the worst.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 ways to improve student safety on campus</title>
      <link>/blog/student-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/student-safety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Providing a safe environment for college and K-12 students is a top priority for campus safety administrators. Student safety is always on the minds of parents and campus safety officers, yet seldom on the mind of the students themselves. So how can those charged with protecting students on campus find relief in an era of increased gun violence and online bullying?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Communications changing, are you behind the curve?</title>
      <link>/blog/mass-notification-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/mass-notification-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mass notification systems have been a staple of human society since language was a thing. Of course, language is necessary for spreading information quickly, but how have humans traditionally communicated to one another en masse? And what does the future hold for mass notification and the systems that support it?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/products/emergency-notification-system/&#34;&gt;Mass communication&lt;/a&gt; isn’t always easy, but it has nonetheless been extremely important throughout human history. To get a deeper understanding of mass communication moving forward, we first have to look to the past to identify the core purpose of shouting a message to the masses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do blue light phones still protect students?</title>
      <link>/blog/blue-light-phones/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/blue-light-phones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve visited a college campus sometime in the last decade or so, chances are you’ve seen emergency blue light phones scattered throughout campus grounds. These tall, blue pillars of safety have been a staple of campus community protection for about 30 years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to create a successful emergency action plan</title>
      <link>/blog/emergency-action-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/emergency-action-plan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Emergencies can happen at any time and they never take place during a time of convenience, which is why formulating an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.osha.gov/etools/evacuation-plans-procedures&#34;&gt;emergency action plan&lt;/a&gt; (EAP) is vital for all organizations. For some organizations, the lack of an EAP can quickly put them out of business when critical situations arise.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Occupational Safety &amp;amp; Health Administration (OSHA) requires written emergency action plans for many businesses. Beyond that, it is a financially sound decision to maintain an emergency action plan:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Up to 40% of businesses affected by a natural or human-caused disaster never reopen.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Customers don’t really care if your business is recovering from a disaster, they still expect their products and services on time or they’ll consider your competitors.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A good EAP will include outreach efforts that will allow your recovering organization to stay on top of the narrative (informing customers, stakeholders, media, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Insurance rarely covers the entire cost of recovering from a disaster and certainly does not account for lost revenue.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Launching and maintaining your student safety app</title>
      <link>/blog/student-safety-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/student-safety-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The decision to implement a student safety app in any campus environment is not to be taken lightly. There are a plethora of safety app options available, which makes legitimate and fair evaluation difficult. There’s also the challenge of imagining how a specific app will perform in your unique school environment. Maybe you have a large, sprawling main campus with several satellite campuses in different parts of the country. Or maybe you’re a small high school with a limited security team. Either way, you need to make sure that your chosen student safety app can thrive in your environment to keep community members safe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So what do you do to make sure this is the case? How do you choose an effective safety app for years to come?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Step one… educate yourself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It may seem obvious, but there’s a lot of information out there to sift through. Let’s package up this information into digestible, organized pieces so you can understand just what a student safety app is supposed to look like and how it can be applied to your specific environment effectively.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are your emergency messages reaching the right people?</title>
      <link>/blog/emergency-messages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/emergency-messages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are the pros and cons of some of the emergency messages platforms available today, as well as suggestions on how to make your emergency alert program more effective. When an emergency happens, campus officials must be able to quickly disseminate critical information so their community members can take appropriate actions to protect themselves and the individuals in their care. How a person responds can vary, depending on their situation and location. They might need to shelter in place, lock down, evacuate or some other action.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, before anyone can respond to an alert, they must first be able to see, hear or read the announcement. Unfortunately, no one type of technology can reach everyone in a campus community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SMS text messaging systems are an excellent way to reach a large number of community members, but these systems generally require a person to register in order to receive notifications. What about people who aren’t registered, such as visitors? What about students in class who have turned off their phones to take a test? What about those who don’t have a mobile phone? How will campus administrators be able to reach these individuals?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Loudspeakers and other types of audible announcements are another effective way of disseminating emergency messages, especially to visitors or others on campus who are not registered for your organization’s SMS text alert system. But what about the individuals on your campus who are hearing-impaired or wearing headphones and can’t hear the emergency announcement?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Digital displays and pop-up computer messages are another excellent option, especially for campuses that have a lot of visitors or individuals who are hard of hearing, or if the loudspeakers aren’t powerful enough for audible announcements to be heard in a loud environment such as a school hallway filled with students. But what about individuals who are sight-impaired? How can campus officials reach them during a crisis?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating College Safety Apps</title>
      <link>/blog/campus-safety-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/campus-safety-apps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Evaluating college safety apps and the vendors providing them can be a challenging and confusing task without the proper guidance. In this guide, we’ll go over some of the essential categories that are necessary for understanding and properly evaluating safety app implementation. Whether you’re a safety app pro or just getting started with this topic, this guide will provide you with some valuable information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Throughout my 30+ years in law enforcement, I’ve had the privilege and honor of working alongside so many selfless people who work behind the scenes to improve their communities. When I first got involved with technologies for campus safety, the possibilities were endless. Could we replace, or at worst, supplement existing blue light towers? Could we streamline ‘See Something, Say Something’ workflows so that powerful information is delivered directly from the community to the right people? These ambitions were exciting to consider, but only with the help of campus first responders was I able to focus these ideas to build a useful solution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s because of these members of the campus law enforcement community, and the kindness they showed me, that I’ve written this guide. It’s my hope that you can find this guide useful and, wherever you end up, feel positively about the process and outcome of your campus safety app evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arkansas school shooting has students afraid to return</title>
      <link>/blog/arkansas-school-shooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/arkansas-school-shooting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Citizens of Pine Bluff, Arkansas are still recovering from the devastating Arkansas school shooting that took place on Monday, March 1st at Watson Chapel Junior High School. The shooting resulted in the death of a 15-year-old boy who was in critical condition before passing away days later. The suspected gunman is a 15-year-old classmate of the victim’s and was found hiding behind a house near the school. The shooting appears to be a ‘targeted incident’ according to local police and the suspect’s motives are still under investigation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workplace Violence Prevention for Health Care and Social Service Workers Act Reintroduced</title>
      <link>/blog/health-care-and-social-service-workers-act/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/health-care-and-social-service-workers-act/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A bipartisan group of House lawmakers has reintroduced the Workplace Violence Prevention for Health Care and Social Service Workers Act.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The bill (H.R. 1195) – introduced by Rep. Joe Courtney (D-CT) on Feb. 22 and co-sponsored by four Republicans and three Democrats – directs OSHA to issue a standard requiring employers in the health care and social services industries develop and implement workplace violence prevention plans to protect nurses, physicians, social workers, emergency responders and others. The proposed federal legislation pertains, not only to hospitals, but also to facilities such as Veterans’ Affairs, the Indian Health Service and home-based hospice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature Focus: COVID Tools, Submit Tip &amp; Resource Tile</title>
      <link>/blog/covid-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/covid-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week’s Feature Focus, where we highlight a specific aspect of the 911Cellular Solution and find out what makes it so valuable. Today’s topic is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/products/mobile-safety-app/&#34;&gt;Mobile Safety App&lt;/a&gt; features that can assist your organization in reopening, remaining open safely, and preventing the spread of COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/blog/911Cellular-Submit-Tip-COVID-Feature.jpg.webp&#34; alt=&#34;=Covid safety app&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Submit Tip feature&lt;/strong&gt; shines for its ability to be customized and molded to fit your organization’s needs. Administrators can create tip categories such as ‘social distancing violation’, ‘unsafe public gathering’, etc. App users can easily and discreetly notify health and safety forces anonymously as well as include helpful pictures and videos. In turn, safety forces have the option to start a conversation with the tip submitter, even if the tip submitter chose to remain anonymous. Additionally, the organization’s Administrators can be proactive in encouraging use of the feature by enabling a ‘See Something, Say Something’ campaign. This campaign will automatically send push notifications to a small portion of your community each day, asking them a question such as ‘have you seen any mask violations lately?’. When an app user clicks into the push notification, they will be taken directly to the Submit Tip feature.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Becoming Alyssa’s Law Compliant 101</title>
      <link>/blog/alyssas-law-compliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/alyssas-law-compliance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On February 14, 2018, a gunman opened fire at Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School in Parkland, Florida, killing 17 people. One of the victims of this horrific tragedy was Alyssa Alhadeff, a 14 year old talented writer and soccer player. In the wake of her daughter’s death, Lori Alhadeff, Alyssa’s mother, took action to prevent future school violence. This is how Alyssa’s law was created.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Alyssa’s  Law?&lt;/strong&gt; Alyssa’s Law is critical legislation which addresses law enforcement response time when a life-threatening emergency occurs. The law calls for the installation of silent panic alarms that are directly linked to law enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The COVID Safety System provides much-needed clarity for your organization</title>
      <link>/blog/covid-safety-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/covid-safety-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The rhythm of our daily life, the decisions we make, and how we operate our organizations have all been deeply affected by the COVID-19 pandemic. For many organizations, the pressure to reopen for economic and social reasons are being heavily weighed against exposure and liability risks. Business owners find themselves with decision paralysis when it comes to determining what a successful and safe reopening process looks like. In order to cut through the confusion and frustration surrounding reopening, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/&#34;&gt;911Cellular&lt;/a&gt; has created the COVID Safety System. If you’re thinking about reopening your facilities, do so safely by reducing the level of uncertainty involving COVID-19 within your organization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bolstering your existing blue light towers</title>
      <link>/blog/blue-light-towers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/blue-light-towers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Blue light towers have been the unrelenting security guards of universities, hospitals, and parks far and wide for decades. The highly recognizable tall, thin, blue towers are a symbol of safety… something to run to if things go wrong during an early morning jog or a late night walk home. The towers provide a way for people to communicate directly with nearby security forces. Some blue lights provide 2-way communication with a dispatch center, while others provide a panic button feature. Due to the prevalence of blue light towers, anyone (at any time) can easily alert security forces that they’re in distress as long as there is a blue light tower in that area.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature Focus: Blue Light Tower System Integration</title>
      <link>/blog/blue-light-tower-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/blue-light-tower-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week’s Feature Focus, where we highlight a specific aspect of the 911Cellular Solution and find out what makes it so valuable. Today we’re focusing on integrating 911Cellular software into your existing blue light tower system.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An easily identifiable symbol of safety, blue light towers can be seen across universities, hospitals, and public spaces nationwide. The premise of the blue light tower is simple, to provide an easy way for the public to notify safety forces in the event of an emergency. Blue light towers remove the need to remember an emergency phone number, dial a phone, or locate a nearby safety officer. Activations made through a blue light tower are typically routed back to an organization’s dispatch center in the form of a phone call or pager notification.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote Deployment During a Pandemic</title>
      <link>/blog/remote-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/remote-deployment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic has emphasized the importance of contactless delivery when it comes to grocery shopping and food delivery. But what about businesses outside of the food industry? How can businesses owners, integrators and other partners sell their products while the majority of people are still working away from the office?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many Americans are still staying home, even as some states begin to reopen, according to an analysis from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/2020/national/map-us-still-staying-home-coronavirus/?itid=hp_hp-banner-main_graphic-stayathome-1140am:homepage/story-ans&#34;&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature Focus: System Wide Multilingual Support</title>
      <link>/blog/multilingual-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/multilingual-support/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week’s Feature Focus, where we highlight a specific aspect of the 911Cellular Solution and find out what makes it so valuable. Today’s topic is multilingual support and the entirety of its reach through various products and services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is offering multilingual support so important?&lt;/strong&gt; According to the United States Census Bureau, there are over 350 languages spoken within the United States. The graph below shows the number of languages spoken based on major metropolitan areas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Predicament for Home Healthcare Workers: Uncontrolled Environments</title>
      <link>/blog/home-healthcare-workers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/home-healthcare-workers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As baby boomers age, the need for nurses and home healthcare workers will continue to climb. The Census bureau expects the number of people &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.census.gov/prod/2014pubs/p25-1140.pdf&#34;&gt;over the age of 65 to nearly double from 2012 to 2050&lt;/a&gt;. In addition to a large aging population, more people are preferring to receive medical treatment and end of life care at home, as opposed to assisted living centers or hospitals. According to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aarp.org/research/topics/community/info-2014/home-community-services-10.html&#34;&gt;2010 AARP survey&lt;/a&gt; nearly 75% of respondents (all age 45+) strongly agreed with the statement, “what I’d really like to do is stay in my current residence for as long as possible”. With more individuals falling in the 65+ age bracket and requesting healthcare at home the demand for nurses and home healthcare workers is skyrocketing. In fact, the demand for home healthcare workers is slated to increase by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bls.gov/ooh/healthcare/home-health-aides-and-personal-care-aides.htm&#34;&gt;36% between 2018 and 2028&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 things your organization should do to prepare for the upcoming climate crisis</title>
      <link>/blog/preempt-emergencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/preempt-emergencies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No organization can fully prepare for every possible scenario, but there are ways to preempt emergencies that can help every organization, regardless of size. Communication remains a key piece to emergency management and preparedness, so we’ve outlined a few ways to get ahead of the curve when it comes to protecting your organization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Addressing Community Pandemic Related Stress</title>
      <link>/blog/pandemic-related-stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/pandemic-related-stress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COVID-19 has presented everyone with a multitude of internal and external pandemic related stress points to grapple with. For some, it’s panic over the loss of a job, depression spawned from extended social isolation, or exhaustion fueled by never ending anxiety. While Netflix, Instagram and other platforms can provide much needed temporary distractions, they both fall short in addressing the root problem. Below are two common stressors that members of your community may be experiencing and some ways that you can help out:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Healthcare heroes are getting assaulted and it&#39;s costing millions</title>
      <link>/blog/violence-against-healthcare-workers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/violence-against-healthcare-workers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2020 the public is visiting hospitals and emergency departments more than ever. An unfortunate parallel increase can be seen in cases of violence against healthcare workers. What are the immediate and long term costs of workplace violence on healthcare organizations? And more importantly,  what can be done to minimize these costs and protect healthcare workers against the steady rise in workplace violence?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Calls are Overwhelming 911 Dispatch Centers</title>
      <link>/blog/covid-19-calls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/covid-19-calls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The number of cases of COVID-19 continue to rise, shelter in place ordinances have rolled out, and in some cases have been extended. Living within a pandemic has left many with questions and few reliable sources for answers. Many individuals have turned to calling 911 for answers to their questions about shelter in place orders and Coronavirus related information. Police departments and emergency dispatchers have become inundated with the severe uptick in COVID-19 calls.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Communicating COVID-19 Protocol to Healthcare Workers</title>
      <link>/blog/covid-19-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/covid-19-protocol/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices for Crisis Communication: Pandemic Communication Outreach</title>
      <link>/blog/pandemic-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/pandemic-communication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The rise and spread of COVID-19 has communities, businesses, and medical facilities scrambling to effectively communicate crucial information within their organizations, and to wider audiences such as patients, students, customers, etc. For many organizations this is the first time they’ve had to implement pandemic communication and mass notification practices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To assist organizations grappling with how to effectively communicate with their community in the midst of the COVID-19 pandemic, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/&#34;&gt;911Cellular&lt;/a&gt; has developed three best practices for effective pandemic communication…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coronavirus Preparedness for Hospitals and Medical Providers Focus: Multilevel Effective Communication Practices</title>
      <link>/blog/coronavirus-preparedness-for-hospitals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/coronavirus-preparedness-for-hospitals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Centers for Disease Control (CDC) released a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/downloads/hospital-preparedness-checklist.pdf&#34;&gt;Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Hospital Preparedness Assessment Tool&lt;/a&gt;. The document outlines six best practices in regards to Coronavirus preparedness for hospitals and medical centers. Hospitals are not required or mandated to follow these six practices. However, they are strongly advised to review and apply them in preparation for potential arrivals of COVID-19 patients. The six best practices for Coronavirus preparedness for hospitals include…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Crisis Management: A Comprehensive Guide</title>
      <link>/blog/crisis-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/crisis-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover how to effectively navigate through crises and minimize their impact with this comprehensive guide on crisis management.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Comprehensive Safety Solution: Made to Fit Your Organization</title>
      <link>/blog/comprehensive-safety-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/comprehensive-safety-solution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot the 911Cellular solution can do for almost any organization, regardless of size or industry… and for that it can be accurately labelled the comprehensive safety solution. But perhaps the most beneficial aspect of the 911Cellular solution is its ability to fit within your organization like a glove.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Feature Focus: App Configuration Elevating Community Safety</title>
      <link>/blog/app-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/app-configuration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this Feature Focus, we’ll touch on App Configuration, which is an incredibly unique and fun feature that allows Administrators to quickly customize their Mobile Safety App in a variety of ways… all completed easily from the 911Cellular Portal. One of the most attractive elements of this feature is that this customization can happen for all Mobile Safety App accounts! This means that even those who did not purchase a white label Mobile Safety App (custom name and icon) can take advantage of these customization tools!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature Focus: The Proactive Submit Tip Feature</title>
      <link>/blog/submit-tip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/submit-tip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this Feature Focus, we’ll cover the all-important, proactive reporting platform known as Submit Tip. The Submit Tip feature is perhaps the most popular of all Mobile Safety App features and the name can be customized to fit your institution’s branding or particular usage (Anonymous Tip, Submit Report, iReport, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Submit Tip allows users to send tips about safety concerns, suspicious activity, maintenance, or general non-emergency information. When submitting a tip, the user’s selected tip category will determine where the tip is received. For instance, a college student who submits a tip about a broken hallway light in their dorm can have their tip sent directly to the maintenance department… instead of wasting the safety department’s time with a tip they can’t act on properly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even more, the tip submitter can also send photo and video attachments to support their tip and the tip submitter can do all of this anonymously, without ever revealing their identity, phone number or any other personal information.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Kent State Shootings of 1970</title>
      <link>/blog/kent-state-shootings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/kent-state-shootings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On May 4th, 1970, Kent State University became the sight of what is now known as the Kent State shootings (or the May 4th massacre). During the incident, four students were killed and 9 others were wounded. The situation was unique because, unlike the mass shootings we are used to hearing about today, the shooting was carried out by multiple armed National Guard soldiers who fired into an unarmed crowd of protestors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mental Toll of School Shootings</title>
      <link>/blog/mental-toll-of-school-shootings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/mental-toll-of-school-shootings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recent news of a shooting in El Paso shows that mass shootings and gun violence still remain a problem in America. The youngest victim was 15 years old, a sophomore in high school.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While news of mass shootings are abhorrent, they’re especially heartbreaking when they occur in schools. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/school-shooting-lessons-learned/&#34;&gt;The incident at Noblesville West Middle School shows that school shootings are traumatic&lt;/a&gt; regardless of how many casualties there are. Schools are meant to be safe spaces for our children to learn and grow as individuals. It doesn’t make sense for us to bid them goodbye every morning knowing that their safety isn’t a given.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thus, school shootings affect the entire community, but this is especially true for the children. Living through a traumatic experience isn’t easy, which means teachers and parents are left struggling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wireless Panic Button Solutions Crucial For Emergency Departments</title>
      <link>/blog/wireless-panic-button/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/wireless-panic-button/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is a complete wireless panic button solution? Why is it important for hospitals and particularly emergency departments to have one?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s not a secret to those who work in the healthcare industry that violence against employees is a major concern. And according to many, that violence is even more prevalent within emergency room departments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a recent survey conducted by ACEP (American College of Emergency Physicians), nearly half (47%) of emergency physicians report being physically assaulted at some point during their career. And almost 70% of emergency physicians say that emergency department violence has increased in the last half decade.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature Focus: HIPS (Hyper-Accurate Indoor Positioning System)</title>
      <link>/blog/hyper-accurate-indoor-positioning-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/hyper-accurate-indoor-positioning-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this Feature Focus, we will dip our toes into the vast ocean of indoor positioning system technology, and why 911Cellular’s HIPS (Hyper-Accurate Indoor Positioning System) is transforming the emergency communications landscape.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature Focus: Emergency Response Teams Keeping Communities Safe</title>
      <link>/blog/emergency-response-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/emergency-response-team/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today we begin a new series, Feature Focus, which will highlight a key piece of the comprehensive 911Cellular emergency communications system. In this Feature Focus, we take a closer look at Emergency Response Team. Within the diverse 911Cellular system of emergency communications, the Emergency Response Team (ERT) plays a vital role in helping to reduce response times for institutions with panic buttons for computers, mobile phones or Bluetooth devices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ugly Reality of Sexual Violence on College Campuses</title>
      <link>/blog/sexual-violence-on-college-campuses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/sexual-violence-on-college-campuses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gun violence is at an all time high in the United States, and college students today have more reasons to worry about their safety than perhaps any other generation preceding them… but most college students also have to worry about acts of sexual violence such as rape and molestation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acts of sexual violence in the United States are a lot more common than many would like to believe… especially in colleges. According to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rainn.org/statistics/campus-sexual-violence&#34;&gt;report by RAINN&lt;/a&gt; (Rape, Abuse &amp;amp; Incest National Network), 11.2% of students experience sexual assault or rape during their college years. This alarming statistic includes both graduate and undergraduate students and is not limited to just women, as men are also susceptible to such acts of violence. Moreover, 4.2% of students are stalked when they start college. Many acts of sexual violence go unreported, so the actual numbers are likely even worse.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bracing For Severe Weather in 2019</title>
      <link>/blog/severe-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/severe-weather/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last two years were quite stressful for large portions of the United States living in areas prone to natural disasters and severe weather. In 2018, the US incurred a record high of $33.79 billion in damages due to 15 storms, eight hurricanes and two major tornadoes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the United States is still under the threat of catastrophic hurricanes and storms, it is slowly becoming essential that various institutions take advantage of severe weather alert systems. 2019 is likely to follow in the footsteps of 2018, bringing about a slew of storms and hurricanes of varying strengths.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Can Be Done to Stop Violence in Healthcare?</title>
      <link>/blog/violence-in-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/violence-in-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-violence-in-healthcare-problem&#34;&gt;The violence in healthcare problem&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Violence against nurses, and violence in healthcare in general, is not a new problem. According to the Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA), incidents of serious workplace violence were four times more common in healthcare than in private industry from 2002 to 2013. And statistics indicate that patients are (by far) the largest source of that violence. 80% of serious violent incidents reported in 2013 were caused by interactions with patients.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Agile Geofencing Within Critical Communication Technology</title>
      <link>/blog/geofencing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/geofencing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-geofencing&#34;&gt;What is geofencing?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Geofencing has become a popular term and buzzword in recent years that carries with it a variety of applications in many markets. Aside from geofencing being used for marketing purposes and in the business to consumer realm, proper use of geofencing technology can be a prime differentiator for companies looking to provide critical communication services and lifesaving solutions to other organizations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But let’s back up for a second and define what a geofence actually is…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why is Common Alerting Protocol Important for Mass Communication?</title>
      <link>/blog/common-alerting-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/common-alerting-protocol/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Various institutions in the United States are finally taking steps to install and implement emergency alert systems, yet what they don’t realize is that many of them are already obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An emergency alert system is one of the most important security elements of any organization, as it ensures the safety of employees. However, as technology is in a constant state of flux and is ever changing, most of the alert systems companies are using have now become obsolete since the introduction of CAP (Common Alerting Protocol) in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Healthcare Institutions are in Dire Need of Mass Communication Systems</title>
      <link>/blog/healthcare-mass-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/healthcare-mass-communication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mass communication refers to multiple mediums that are used to contact a large number of people or individuals in an instant. These systems are sometimes limited to emergency systems only. On the contrary, mass communication systems have the potential to improve the overall level of communication in an organization, and healthcare institutions can benefit greatly from these systems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The benefits of using healthcare mass communication systems outweigh those of using conventional communications systems. It has been proven over time that the multiple means of contacting a person via call, text, email and social media maximizes the possibility of reaching that person.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Following are some basic benefits of using mass communications systems in healthcare facilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The importance of workplace panic button implementation</title>
      <link>/blog/workplace-panic-buttons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/workplace-panic-buttons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Workplace panic button implementations are a vital security measure that every enterprise should deploy, but with more affordable software technologies being developed, even small businesses are beginning to benefit from these crucial, life-saving solutions. Workplaces often take various measures in order to ensure that their employees feel safe in their working environment. This is helpful in boosting their productivity and makes them feel more relaxed, but it also can reduce the liability of an organization based on the reduced severity and quantity of incidents that tend to occur after workplace panic button implementation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why You Need a Business Emergency Communication Plan</title>
      <link>/blog/business-emergency-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/business-emergency-communication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Any company, regardless of the work they do or the market they operate in, should always be planning for business emergency communication. Catastrophic events do not occur at a certain time or with any given warning; rather, they can be spontaneous and completely random.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is why every business should have a mass notification system that will allow you to properly communicate with your workforce in a catastrophic event.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Sure Your Campus Safety App Awareness Campaign is Successful</title>
      <link>/blog/campus-safety-app-awareness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/campus-safety-app-awareness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking to upgrade safety on your college campus? A campus safety app for students, staff, faculty and visitors may be on your list of potential safety solutions for your community. If so, it’s important to understand the full scope of campus safety app awareness. Reliability, multi-functionality, and usability are all very important factors to consider when looking at different safety app products, but perhaps less obvious is the level of awareness of the app within your campus community. An app that functions perfectly will ultimately be rendered useless if the community its supposed to protect is unaware of its existence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So how can you make sure that a company with a safety app product will help you raise awareness after launch?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’ve come up with a few specific questions to ask that will give you a better understanding of the community awareness plan in place for each company you speak to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proactive Hospital Safety A Priority for 2019</title>
      <link>/blog/proactive-hospital-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/proactive-hospital-safety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The value of creating and maintaining a proactive hospital safety program for hospital employees is gaining traction nationwide. Workplace violence against hospital staff members is not uncommon… and it affects employees stationed within soft areas where patients or family members may be volatile after receiving poor medical news – or for other reasons.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kcchronicle.com/2018/09/20/state-police-report-on-delnor-shooting-details-nurses-terror/aba8tfl/&#34;&gt;An incident at a Geneva, Illinois hospital&lt;/a&gt; in 2017, in which a nurse was taken hostage and raped by an armed felon recovering from surgery, was one instance that prompted a new bill to be formed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2018: K-12 School Gun Violence Review For The Year</title>
      <link>/blog/k-12-school-gun-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/k-12-school-gun-violence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chds.us/ssdb/&#34;&gt;study from the US Naval Postgraduate School&lt;/a&gt;, 2018 was a particularly bad year for K-12 school gun violence. There were 94 K-12 school gun violence incidents this year, the most since 1970 (which is where the data starts). In 2006, there were 59 (the next highest on record).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When looking at the data from the perspective of lives lost, 2018 was also the worst year on record. So far, 55 people have died (including the shooter) this year in K-12 school gun violence incidents. The next highest death toll by year was in 1993 (40).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>School Shooting Lessons Learned: Noblesville West Middle School</title>
      <link>/blog/school-shooting-lessons-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/school-shooting-lessons-learned/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, Indiana county leaders gathered to attend the Indiana Association of County Commissioners in an effort to discuss the lessons learned from the Noblesville West Middle School Shooting that took place earlier this year. On May 25th, 2018, a 13-year old student and her teacher were shot during the incident before the suspect was wrestled to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the first time since the shooting happened, commissioners had the chance to hear directly from the people in Hamilton County who responded to the scene that day. The main takeaway: being prepared makes a big difference in these types of situations. Before the time of the shooting, Hamilton County’s Emergency Management team hosted multiple active shooter training drills with local police, fire and medical personnel in specific scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Our Schools Safe While Providing Inclusive School Safety Solutions</title>
      <link>/blog/inclusive-school-safety-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/inclusive-school-safety-solutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amidst all the shouting about protecting our students at school, are we ready to provide inclusive school safety solutions? This past year has been filled with tragedy in our country’s classrooms as we reflect on the school violence that took place and the lives that were lost. The days, weeks and months following each tragic event often included strong words and swift action by federal and local officials. Proposed solutions have included such things as; increasing the presence of school police and security, arming teachers and staff, increasing surveillance and also implementing some tougher disciplinary practices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Can Colleges Get Students to Report Hazing Tips?</title>
      <link>/blog/report-hazing-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/report-hazing-tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Penn State University and other higher education institutions are trying to find ways to encourage students to report hazing tips. For Penn State, this comes after the tragic death of 19 year old Timothy Piazza, who died during a hazing incident at Beta Theta Pi’s pledge acceptance party in February of 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;20 months later Pennsylvania now has some of the strictest hazing laws in the country after Governor Tom Wolf’s signing of the ‘Timothy J. Piazza Anti-Hazing law’. The new law will strengthen penalties for hazing while also providing safeguards for protecting students. The increased penalties can include felony charges, while those who call police during a hazing incident will receive immunity from prosecution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will School Safety Politics Affect Young Voter Turnout?</title>
      <link>/blog/voting-school-safety-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/voting-school-safety-politics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Young voters in America have historically shown a low percentage of voting participation, but this year… school safety politics might change that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the last 20 years, no more than 20 percent of those age 18 to 24 have gone to the polls to voice their opinions during a midterm election. This year could be different.. according to an Education Week study which surveyed the youngest eligible voters, nearly two-thirds of respondents said they plan to vote this year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASU Dealing With Campus Sexual Violence In Creative Ways</title>
      <link>/blog/campus-sexual-violence-creative-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/campus-sexual-violence-creative-solution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Arizona State University is attempting to fight the growing issue of campus sexual violence in a way that counters many other institutions’ reactions to the problem. Instead of only increasing security resources or safety technology, ASU is addressing the problem by proactively engaging and educating its students through CounterAct, a multidisciplinary, campus-wide effort to reduce sexual assault and center healthy sexuality using the arts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The initiative is brought in partnership with ASU’s Herberger Institute for Design and the Arts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovative Technology in Hospital Security</title>
      <link>/blog/funding-helps-stop-school-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/funding-helps-stop-school-violence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The US Department of Justice recently announced that more than $70 million in grant funding will go to over 220 jurisdictions across the country through the STOP School Violence Act. The money will provide support for school security, student and faculty training, and to aid law enforcement officers and first responders during incidents of school violence. The funding can also support new or existing crisis intervention teams.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The DOJ will also invest $1 million toward research on the factors that lead to mass shootings. Less than a week prior to this announcement, Attorney General Jeff Sessions announced $200,000 in funding for the National Association of School Resource Officers, which will help the organization expand and train more personnel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KSU Gun-Rights Rally Attracts Attention From Protesters &amp; Police</title>
      <link>/blog/ksu-gun-rights-rally/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/ksu-gun-rights-rally/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Former Kent State University student Kaitlin Bennett attempted to organize a gun-rights rally late last week for activists to protest KSU’s no firearm policy on campus for students, faculty and staff. After KSU said it would charge her group several thousand dollars for security costs, Bennett decided to announce plans for a walk instead. Bennett expected about 200 people to walk with her around KSU’s campus in support of second amendment rights including campus carry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protesters Focus on Effort to Occupy University Police Offices</title>
      <link>/blog/protesters-occupy-university-police/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/protesters-occupy-university-police/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly 3 months ago, Jason Washington, a 45 year old Navy veteran, was shot and killed by Portland State University police officers after being told by police to drop his friend’s gun during a street fight. Jason was trying to de-escalate the fight, according to witnesses and body cam footage, that started when his friend, Jeremy Wilkinson, used a racial slur and threw a stranger’s phone.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On Monday, students and protesters made demands as their rallies turned into an effort to occupy university police offices. Protesters say they will occupy the space until their demands are met: the immediate disarmament of PSU police officers, the firing of the officers involved in the case, and a permanent memorial to Jason Washington erected on campus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Students Demand Accountability After Sexual Assault Lawsuit</title>
      <link>/blog/sexual-assault-lawsuit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/sexual-assault-lawsuit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, students at University of Maryland – Baltimore County met to share their experiences with sexual assault after a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.baltimoresun.com/news/maryland/crime/bs-md-umbc-lawsuit-20180915-story.html&#34;&gt;class-action sexual assault lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; was filed claiming that UMBC maintains a culture of covering up sexual abuse. Eventually their meeting turned into a march, with over 100 students and followers tagging along and chanting ‘No means no…” as they made their way up the campus administration building to meet with UMBC President Freeman A. Hrabowski III.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Plan to Mobilize School Safety Agents in NYC</title>
      <link>/blog/school-safety-agents/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/school-safety-agents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to New York City Mayor Bill de Blasio, last week was the start of a pilot program at multiple Bronx schools that will turn school safety agents into unarmed beat cops, roaming the halls and tasked with looking for wandering students, conversing with the students, identifying suspicious activity, and meeting with principals to discuss potential conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The point of all this is to try and mobilize the city’s school safety agents who currently stand or sit idly at entrances while requesting ID from visitors. Also, it’s an attempt to help cultivate active relationships between the safety officers and their community of students, teachers, parents and staff. Just the notion of having a school safety agent that students can feel comfortable speaking to on a daily basis can go a long way in helping to diffuse situations of distress and anxiety… and if nothing else, will hopefully work as a safety valve to relieve pressure from those in need.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changes to Sexual Misconduct Policies on Campuses Nationwide</title>
      <link>/blog/sexual-misconduct-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/sexual-misconduct-policies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Department of Education is proposing new Title IX changes that will affect sexual misconduct policies on campuses nationwide. The new changes will seek to bolster the rights of the accused, while also protecting colleges from increased liability and giving more support for victims.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A 2011 letter written by the Obama administration encouraged schools to address sexual misconduct on their own, which led many of these schools to run quasi-judicial systems in order to get to the bottom of each issue. Coupled with an expanded definition of sexual harassment, and how schools should approach dealing with it, many believed that those accused of sexual harassment didn’t stand a fighting chance and were deemed ‘guilty’ from the start.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Florida Shootings Spark Talk of Proactive Safety Measures</title>
      <link>/blog/florida-shootings-proactive-safety-measures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/florida-shootings-proactive-safety-measures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Residents, students and employees within the state of Florida can agree on one thing… it’s important to start taking proactive safety measures in order to halt the all too common mass shooting events that keep happening in the southern state. The discussion diverges from there, with several viewpoints on both sides of the political spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Florida’s recent history with mass shootings is appalling… in 2016, 49 were killed at the Pulse nightclub in Orlando. In 2017, five died in the Fort Lauderdale airport shooting. And so far in 2018, two more shootings on Florida soil… 17 were killed in the Parkland shooting at Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School, and three died, including the gunman, at the most recent shooting that took place at a Madden video game tournament in Jacksonville.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tennessee Gives School Security Funding Statewide</title>
      <link>/blog/school-security-funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/school-security-funding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;State-wide safety reviews of nearly every public school in the state of Tennessee were recently conducted and completed for the first time ever. This comes after Tennessee Governor Bill Haslam announced the plans in March. As a result of the reviews being completed, Tennessee will be handing out unprecedented school security funding across the state.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The reviews were suggested by the School Safety Working Group established by Governor Haslam after the February Parkland, FL school shooting that killed 17 and injured 17 more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wildfires &amp; Communication</title>
      <link>/blog/wildfire-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/wildfire-communication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Communication during wildfires is crucial.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s been a devastating wildfire season so far in 2018. West coast residents have been exposed to 16 major wildfires that have burned more than 300,000 acres. The size of these wildfires are particularly troubling, as are their proximity to inhabited communities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many residents are seeing their homes burn despite taking the recommended precautions (creating defensible space and using non-flammable building materials). In some cases, the flame wall can ignite homes from half a mile away, with embers flying above rivers and roads to set the homes ablaze.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Colorado Arming Teachers in 30 Districts</title>
      <link>/blog/colorado-is-arming-teachers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/colorado-is-arming-teachers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The state of Colorado is allowing districts to give teachers the ability to carry guns in school without needing to disclose any information to the state itself. This move, the latest attempt to improve K-12 safety, is not entirely unprecedented; Colorado joins at least 9 other states which are allowing teachers to carry firearms if their district allows it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Those skeptical of this approach have cited a lack of formal, mandatory training for those who will be carrying inside the state’s schools. In fact, the Colorado law allows school boards to designate teachers and staff as security officers (able to carry weapons) without any training. In many areas, the training policy is being created based on requirements from a school’s liability insurance company, not by law enforcement professionals or the state. These training requirements currently include 4 hours of classroom instruction, 12 hours of shooting range training, a total of 24 hours of firearm training over the past four years, 6 hours of active shooter training, and a test that must be passed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Federal Commission on School Safety Meets</title>
      <link>/blog/federal-commission-on-school-safety-meets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/federal-commission-on-school-safety-meets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Federal Commission on School Safety met Thursday, June 21st in Washington D.C. This is the second meeting of the school safety commission, which was created by President Trump in March of 2018 after the deadly Parkland, FL school shooting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Commission, which is led by U.S. Secretary of Education Betsy DeVos, chose to focus on the link between media and school violence. Controversy was started when, on Tuesday, Chairperson DeVos indicated that the commission on school safety will not be investigating the role that guns play in these incidents. Her statement, made in response to a question posed by Democratic Senator Patrick Leahy during a subcommittee hearing, bothered several groups who have taken the lead on the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workplace Injury Reports Subject to Manipulation</title>
      <link>/blog/workplace-injury-reports-subject-to-manipulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/workplace-injury-reports-subject-to-manipulation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a vote that took place this past Wednesday, the Senate, led by Republicans, were able to pass a bill (50-48 vote) that reduces the length large companies are required to keep workplace injury report violations from five years to six months. This vote effectively repeals an Obama administration change that forced employers to keep more detailed workplace injury records and to keep them for longer. OSHA officials have gone on record already, claiming that this new standard does not allow for the proper time to investigate workplace injury reports before employers can destroy them. “This will give license to employers to keep fraudulent records and to willfully violate the law with impunity,” said Debbie Berkowitz, a former OSHA policy adviser.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Event Safety Relevant Now More Than Ever</title>
      <link>/blog/event-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/event-safety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the World Cup starting this week, most of us are thinking about the matches, festivities and glory. But for those who are tasked with providing event safety, the soccer is likely near the back of their minds. Event safety can be extremely complicated, especially for an event that spans a full month and covers an entire county (in this case, a country that is almost an entire continent). Event safety complications arise from both inside and outside the venues. Especially in soccer, where fans are notorious for their extra-curricular fights (see the movie Green Street Hooligans for more insight).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Safety Solutions for Cities</title>
      <link>/blog/safety-solutions-for-cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/safety-solutions-for-cities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are so many safety solutions for cities that are not always well known to the public, and we’d like to help share some information to keep you safe in your hometown.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Keeping a city safe is like building a house. It needs to start with a good foundation, then it requires a lot of work and the proper tools. You can’t build a house with just a hammer, no matter how good that hammer is. We offer tools that assist police departments and citizens. Safety solutions for cities can come in the form of app systems like ours, where we offer a security system in your pocket. 911Cellular offers &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/app-systems/&#34;&gt;PublicShield&lt;/a&gt;, which gives you the ability to receive mass notifications from city officials, gives you direct access to police with an app that can send out your exact location to emergency personnel in case of an emergency, and gives you the ability to share tips or suspicious activity (along with pictures or video) anonymously to your police department.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hospitals aren&#39;t safe places for these individuals</title>
      <link>/blog/hospital-safety-and-eliminating-workplace-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/hospital-safety-and-eliminating-workplace-violence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hospital safety isn’t something the average person thinks about. Hospitals are where we go for emergencies, surgeries, births, and general ailments. As a patient of hospitals, we think of the staff as our care providers. What most people don’t know is that between 2011 and 2013, nearly 75% of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fiercehealthcare.com/healthcare/workplace-violence-healthcare-underreported-and-often-ignored&#34;&gt;workplace assaults&lt;/a&gt; took place in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fiercehealthcare.com/finance/violence-cost-hospitals-2-7b-2016-aha-report-finds&#34;&gt;healthcare settings&lt;/a&gt;. While we are getting treated for our health issues, the staff in our hospitals are getting assaulted by their patients or the patient’s family members/friends. This is a very serious issue, and one that we don’t hear about often enough.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sexual Assault Awareness Month</title>
      <link>/blog/sexual-assault-awareness-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/sexual-assault-awareness-month/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;April is Sexual Assault Awareness Month, and we feel that this is important to talk about; especially for college students.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why is it important for us to talk about sexual assault and how it pertains to college students? Here are just a few statistics:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;20% – 25% of college women and 15% of college men are victims of forced sex during their time in college &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nsvrc.org/statistics#footnote-b&#34;&gt;(b)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A 2002 study revealed that 63.3% of men at one university who self-reported acts qualifying as rape or attempted rape admitted to committing repeat rapes &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nsvrc.org/statistics#footnote-h&#34;&gt;(h)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;More than 90% of sexual assault victims on college campuses do not report the assault &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nsvrc.org/statistics#footnote-b&#34;&gt;(b)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;27% of college women have experienced some form of unwanted sexual contact &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nsvrc.org/statistics#footnote-e&#34;&gt;(e)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nearly two thirds of college students experience sexual harassment &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nsvrc.org/statistics#footnote-p&#34;&gt;(p)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’ve touched on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/campus-security-questions/&#34;&gt;Clery Act&lt;/a&gt; in the past, and we’ve talked about the Clery Act on our social media pages. The Clery Act allows parents and students to see the your school’s security reports. This is important because you want to know how safe your college campus is. You will most likely not see the true numbers for victims of sexual assault because so many go unreported, but you will get a general idea of how safe the campus is. Is your college campus doing enough to keep you safe and to allow you to report assault?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>National School Walkout and School Safety</title>
      <link>/blog/national-school-walkout-school-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/national-school-walkout-school-safety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, we ran some polls on our social media accounts and asked our readers if they felt that the National School Walkouts would help change gun laws and help with school safety. Instead of answering “yes” or “no”, most people answered “hopefully”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No matter what your stance is on gun laws and gun control, I think most people will agree that there needs to be some changes made within the schools to keep our students safe. We have a gun violence issue, and it needs to be dealt with, As I’m writing this, i’m watching the news about yet another school shooting in Maryland. This is unacceptable. We, the adults that are able to vote and have our voices heard, must stand up for our children and be advocates for their safety and well being.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>911Cellular is named one of the Top Government Tech Solution Providers of 2018</title>
      <link>/blog/911cellular-is-named-one-of-the-top-government-tech-solution-providers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/911cellular-is-named-one-of-the-top-government-tech-solution-providers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;911Cellular is named one of the Top Government Tech Solution Providers of 2018 in CIO Applications Magazine. CIO Magazine sat down with Chad Salahshour, the President and CEO of 911Cellular, to talk about how 911Cellular came to fruition. Chad is still actively involved with a local police department, and it’s because of his law enforcement background that he created and started implementing our lifesaving technology across the country. 911Cellular works with dispatchers and smartphone users to open up the lines of emergency communication and to pinpoint your location during an emergency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Communication During Active Shooter Situations</title>
      <link>/blog/effective-communication-active-shooter-situations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/effective-communication-active-shooter-situations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If there is one thing that all experts can agree on, it’s the importance of effective communication during active shooter situations. Schools and even some larger corporations now implement Active Shooter drills, and go over the instructions on what to do in this type of crisis. We want to share some tips on how to effectively communicate if you’re ever in the unfortunate situation where a shooting does take place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>School Shootings: Can we prevent them?</title>
      <link>/blog/school-shootings-can-we-prevent-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/school-shootings-can-we-prevent-them/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;School shootings are becoming increasingly more common, and we find ourselves asking “Can we stop school shootings from happening?”  There is no way to ensure school shooting prevention, but we would like to share some information that may be useful when it comes to creating a school and home environment that may be beneficial to putting an end to some of the violence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Strength-based support. This is a phrase you may have seen before, and we’ll explain exactly what it means. All too often, active school shooters feel alienated and alone. They feel like outcasts. If you can identify a student that is having a hard time in mainstream classes, but may have great artistic ability or they really enjoy coding in computer class, you can offer them strength-based support. Find those kids and offer them incentives to strengthen their areas of expertise. Corrective teaching is great for most students; helping them identify their weaknesses and working to correct those issues. But children who suffer tremendous isolation will only feel MORE isolated in that type of learning environment. By nurturing students that feel like they’re outcasts, we may be able to prevent school shootings.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Schools can offer guidance from a Relationship Officer. These can be guidance counselors, teachers, or other facility members that offer support to students who’s home lives may not have strong adult role models. Schools can also employ a Relationship Officer. These are different from counselors. Their goals are to connect with students and offer them a healthy adult/student relationship that will open the doors to trust and acceptance.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you see something, report it. Whether it’s bullying, signs of abuse, signs of malnourishment, or anything that’s way outside the norm. Most active school shooters acted violently because of extreme bullying or deep feelings of isolation. We can prevent school shootings by making sure all students feel cared for. A lot of schools are overwhelmed and it’s hard to report every single incident, but it’s the one way to ensure that everything is being documented and if there are enough incidents with one student, you will be able to determine that there is a pattern. Counties are also juggling more work than most can handle, but creating a paper trail WILL help in the long run. Even if you’re the only one that sees the paper trail, at least you’ll be able to easily identify a student that could be a risk or at risk.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Talk to your children about mental health, and let them know that there is no stigma involved with needed to talk to someone. We would much rather see a large influx of children talking to therapists as opposed to children shooting up schools. If you think your own child may need help, there is no shame in getting them into therapy. You haven’t failed as a parent; you are actually doing them a favor by getting them the help they need. We know you would rather see your child get help and potentially stop them from becoming an active school shooter. Most counties and cities even offer free services.  Children Services would much rather help you get the resources you need instead of taking a child from your home or worse, putting your child into a detention center. Do not be afraid to contact Children Services or your child’s school if you feel there are psychological issues. You might be surprised to learn that Children Services also offers support groups for parents, and you as a parent may benefit from them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Keeping our children safe should be our number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Look into Geofencing and how it can keep you safe every single day.</title>
      <link>/blog/a-look-into-geofencing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/a-look-into-geofencing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re going to be taking a look into geofencing. You may have heard of a geofence before, but never thought about how it pertains to you and your safety. A lot of apps use geofencing nowadays, and you can even use it to set reminders for yourself. If you’re heading home and need to pick up your dry-cleaning, you can set a geofencing reminder to let you know when you’re nearing the dry cleaners. This is a great resource to look at the simplicity of geofencing in your personal life: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howtogeek.com/221077/htg-explains-what-geofencing-is-and-why-you-should-be-using-it/&#34;&gt;https://www.howtogeek.com/221077/htg-explains-what-geofencing-is-and-why-you-should-be-using-it/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choosing a Mass Notification System</title>
      <link>/blog/massnotificationsystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/massnotificationsystem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mass Notification Systems are important for communities (meaning anything from school campuses to cities) and it can be overwhelming if you don’t know what you NEED in a Mass Notification System. There is a lot of information out there, and a lot of that information can seem too technical for you to understand. We would like to take some time to break down what the ideal Mass Notification System will offer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Staying Safe on NYE</title>
      <link>/blog/staying-safe-on-nye/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/staying-safe-on-nye/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NYE can be such a fun holiday, but it’s important to stay safely enjoy the night. New Year’s Eve sees the highest percentage of deaths related to alcohol. Almost half of all car accidents on NYE and New Year’s Day are due to drinking and driving.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t yet, please download Uber or Lyft and familiarize yourself with the apps. You can also save a cab company’s phone number in your phone. But if you’re planning on drinking, don’t plan on driving. A $30 Uber ride is much cheaper than a DUI or worse… Do NOT drink and drive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coping with Holiday Depression</title>
      <link>/blog/coping-holiday-depression/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/coping-holiday-depression/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Depression is hard to deal with at any given time, but it’s especially difficult during the holidays. You feel like you’re expected to feel the same “holiday joy” that everyone else is feeling, and you don’t want to ruin anyone else’s spirits by telling them that you’re depressed. You then feel more isolated and even more alone.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Holiday depression shouldn’t be battled alone.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The fact is, you’re definitely not alone. In fact, the are a ton of people that feel that the holidays are the worst time of the year. People who don’t have clinical depression or deal with high levels of stress can be miserable around the holidays.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#MeToo, the Silence Breakers, and our Stance on Assault</title>
      <link>/blog/metoo-silence-breakers-stance-assault/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/metoo-silence-breakers-stance-assault/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Time Magazine recently just made the &amp;ldquo;Silence Breakers&amp;rdquo;; the women (and some men) who came forward to talk about sexual assault or harassment, their people of the Year. This is a significant step in the right direction as far as providing people an outlet to share their stories and feel safer coming forward when they’ve been attacked or assaulted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We talk about the Clery Act often, and we consider ourselves to be be well informed and knowledgable about the Clery Act. It is important for you to know about what the Clery Act is and how it can affect you or your child’s safety on campus. The institution’s police department or security departments are required to maintain a public log of all crimes reported to them, or those of which they are made aware. These public logs should be made available on college websites or by the request of the student or the parent(s) of the student. No student should ever feel afraid to tell campus police or trusted officials about a rape that occurred or an assault that took place. If a movement like #MeToo can make students feel safer and give them the ability to talk about something that happened to them, then we support that movement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Guide to Holiday Safety</title>
      <link>/blog/holiday-safety-tips-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/holiday-safety-tips-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The holidays are always fun. Shopping for gifts for your loved ones, finding great deals online, and going on holiday vacations are just a few of the things that most of us look forward to. But unfortunately, holidays are also a time where holiday safety issues arise, but we very rarely do we think about holiday safety and it’s importance. So we wanted to give you holiday safety tips that you can use to safeguard yourself, your home, and your loved ones. These holiday safety tips are things that you can practice all of the time; not just during the holidays.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CSU Partnered with Constantino’s to Promote Campus Safety!</title>
      <link>/blog/csu-constantinos-promote-campus-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/csu-constantinos-promote-campus-safety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Constantino’s Cafe&lt;/strong&gt; on Euclid Ave in Cleveland is a new business that opened up not too long ago, but they’re already making an impact in their community. They’ve decided to promote campus safety by partnering up with &lt;strong&gt;Cleveland State University&lt;/strong&gt; to help raise awareness of the &lt;strong&gt;Viking Shield&lt;/strong&gt; safety app through a local business promotion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Constantino’s is giving away a free small cup of coffee to those that have downloaded Viking Shield on their phones. The Cleveland State Police Department was given 1,000 promotional cards to pass out to students on campus, as well as given them to other people (resident assistants, student organizations, etc.) to help pass out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holiday Safety Tips</title>
      <link>/blog/holiday-safety-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/holiday-safety-tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-short-guide-to-holiday-safety&#34;&gt;A Short Guide to Holiday Safety&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s safe to say that many of you out there are quite fond of the holiday season. There’s spending time with the family, delicious foods and treats (which gives me a reason to take a “brief” break from exercise) and just the sense of something magical and heart-warming in the air. However, despite the child-like wonder feeling in the atmosphere, the holiday season also holds many perils. Now, if you went out for Black Friday shopping (you’re much braver than I!) and survived, you’re half way through the dangerous part! But we still all have a month of battling Mother Nature, rival shoppers/drivers and in-laws left, so don’t let your guard down just yet!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>University Safety Apps: A New Recruiting Tool</title>
      <link>/blog/university-safety-apps-new-recruiting-tool-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/university-safety-apps-new-recruiting-tool-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;university-safety-apps-can-increase-enrollment-heres-what-you-need-to-know&#34;&gt;University Safety Apps Can Increase Enrollment. Here’s What You Need To Know:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With fierce competition for students, universities of all sizes are looking for ways to gain a competitive advantage that attracts prospective students. Despite the fact that safety consistently ranks among the most important factors among applicants, police department and college safety forces are often viewed internally as cost centers; adding to the expense column and not generating revenue. This perception of police and campus safety forces is so deeply ingrained into the higher education system that some departments struggle to even obtain the necessary tools and equipment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Campus Security Questions</title>
      <link>/blog/campus-security-common-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/campus-security-common-questions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;campus-visits--what-to-ask&#34;&gt;Campus Visits – What to Ask&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Visiting campuses and going to school open houses is one of the most exciting times in a young adult’s life, and one of the scariest times for parents. You’re sending your child off to someplace that’s not your home for four years! As parents, we have to think of the practical questions we should be asking during campus tours.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve compiled a list of questions that you may want to consider asking when you&amp;rsquo;re touring campuses. Every school has to be able to answer these types of questions. Thanks to the Clery Act, schools have to make their security reports public knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Salisbury University Safety and 911Shield</title>
      <link>/blog/salisbury-university-safety-911-shield/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/salisbury-university-safety-911-shield/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the common threads among universities that are ranked among the safest schools across the country is the implementation of safety app systems. Salisbury University is a great partner of ours and we wanted to share a great article they wrote about the importance of safety on campus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>911Cellular is your one-stop shop for all critical incident management tools and integrations.</title>
      <link>/critical-incident-management-system-thank-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/critical-incident-management-system-thank-you/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>911Cellular is your one-stop shop for all critical incident management tools and integrations.</title>
      <link>/critical-incident-management-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/critical-incident-management-system/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Collaborative, Innovative Vision for Partnerships</title>
      <link>/partnerships/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/partnerships/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A layered approach to caregiver safety</title>
      <link>/lander/healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/lander/healthcare/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Era for Wearable Panic Buttons Has Arrived: The BadgeR&#43;</title>
      <link>/products/wearable-panic-buttons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/products/wearable-panic-buttons/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A WiFi, Wireless Wall Mounted Panic Button Solution</title>
      <link>/products/wallmounted-panic-buttons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/products/wallmounted-panic-buttons/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Account Deletion - 911Cellular</title>
      <link>/account-deletion-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/account-deletion-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;911cellular-account-deletion-guide&#34;&gt;911Cellular Account Deletion Guide&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;div id=&#34;branding&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;div id=&#34;location-policy&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;contacting-us&#34;&gt;Contacting Us&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If there are any questions regarding account deletion, you may contact us using the information below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://911Cellular.com&#34;&gt;911cellular.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;6001 Cochran Road&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Solon, OH 44139&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;United States&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:Support@911Cellular.com&#34;&gt;Support@911Cellular.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last Edited on 12-07-2023&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All-in-one safety solution for communities</title>
      <link>/industries/public-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/industries/public-safety/</guid>
      <description>Provide your community members with an all-in-one solution for emergency communication, service needs, tip submission, community resources and more. No matter the situation, they&amp;rsquo;ll always be in touch with the right people at the right time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alyssa’s Law Updates &amp; Solutions for Compliance</title>
      <link>/alyssas-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/alyssas-law/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are your emergency messages reaching the right people?</title>
      <link>/ebooks/are-your-emergency-messages-reaching-the-right-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/ebooks/are-your-emergency-messages-reaching-the-right-people/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Campus Safety 101 | Everything you need to know about campus safety</title>
      <link>/campus-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/campus-safety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-to-campus-safety&#34;&gt;Introduction to campus safety&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Campus safety is always a major consideration for campus authorities when creating and maintaining a healthy campus environment. Though many in the United States may think of colleges and universities when the word &amp;lsquo;campus&amp;rsquo; comes to mind, in reality, campus environments can be found within hospital systems, businesses and K-12 school districts as well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A campus is traditionally defined as a piece of land where a series of buildings (usually owned by one institution) combines with outdoor, recreational areas (like parks). The challenges related to keeping a campus safe are varied by the size and type of institution, but it&amp;rsquo;s no secret that campuses can be difficult to keep safe. With both indoor and outdoor spaces, along with potentially large, multi-story buildings, it would be impossible to constantly monitor every corner and dark pathway of any campus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Campus Safety Apps | Student Engagement Matters</title>
      <link>/ebooks/campus-safety-apps-student-engagement-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/ebooks/campus-safety-apps-student-engagement-matters/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Complete Guide to Panic Buttons in Healthcare</title>
      <link>/ebooks/complete-guide-to-panic-buttons-in-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/ebooks/complete-guide-to-panic-buttons-in-healthcare/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Complete Guide to Panic Buttons in Healthcare</title>
      <link>/healthcare-panic-button-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/healthcare-panic-button-guide/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computer Panic Buttons | Discreetly Signal for Assistance</title>
      <link>/computer-panic-buttons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/computer-panic-buttons/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configure Your BadgeR&#43;</title>
      <link>/getstarted/badgerp/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/getstarted/badgerp/admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This guide is intended for system administrators at organizations implementing and distributing the BadgeR+ Wearable Duress Button&lt;/strong&gt;. If you are looking for instructions for everyday use of your BadgeR+, view the &lt;a href=&#34;/getstarted/badgerp&#34;&gt;BadgeR+ User Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;System administrators should be familiar with the content in both this BadgeR+ Admin &amp;amp; Configuration Guide and also the BadgeR+ User Guide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align:center;margin:50px 0px;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9jqC_dMZiEc&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-badger-device&#34;&gt;The BadgeR+ Device&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let’s first get familiar with the BadgeR+ Wearable Duress Button and its components. Here is an overview snapshot of the device:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact Alyssa&#39;s Law Experts - 911Cellular</title>
      <link>/contact-alyssas-law-experts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/contact-alyssas-law-experts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us - 911Cellular</title>
      <link>/contact-us-thank-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/contact-us-thank-you/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us - 911Cellular</title>
      <link>/contact-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/contact-us/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emergency Alert System, Safety App and Panic Button company</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everything You Need to Know About Campus Safety</title>
      <link>/ebooks/everything-you-need-to-know-about-campus-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/ebooks/everything-you-need-to-know-about-campus-safety/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finally an Easy-to-Use Emergency Notification System</title>
      <link>/products/emergency-notification-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/products/emergency-notification-system/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FREE eBook: Multimodal Mass Notification</title>
      <link>/multimodal-mass-notification-lander-thank-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/multimodal-mass-notification-lander-thank-you/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FREE eBook: Multimodal Mass Notification</title>
      <link>/multimodal-mass-notification-lander/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/multimodal-mass-notification-lander/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FREE eBook: The Complete Guide to Panic Buttons in Healthcare</title>
      <link>/healthcare-lander/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/healthcare-lander/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FREE eBook: Workplace Violence Prevention</title>
      <link>/workplace-violence-lander-thank-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/workplace-violence-lander-thank-you/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FREE eBook: Workplace Violence Prevention</title>
      <link>/workplace-violence-lander/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/workplace-violence-lander/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hospital Violence and Critical Communication Solutions for Healthcare</title>
      <link>/industries/healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/industries/healthcare/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Campus Safety Solutions for Higher Education</title>
      <link>/industries/higher-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/industries/higher-education/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>K-12 School Safety Solutions | Achieve Alyssa&#39;s Law Compliance</title>
      <link>/industries/k12schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/industries/k12schools/</guid>
      <description>After exhaustive deliberation, the Florida Department of Education&amp;rsquo;s Selection Committee rated 911Cellular as the #1 mobile panic alert system for Alyssa&amp;rsquo;s Law compliance in 2021.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keyboard Panic Buttons | Staff duress and communication response system</title>
      <link>/keyboard-panic-buttons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/keyboard-panic-buttons/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Partner With Us - 911Cellular</title>
      <link>/contact-us-partners-thank-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/contact-us-partners-thank-you/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Partner With Us - 911Cellular</title>
      <link>/contact-us-partners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/contact-us-partners/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy - 911Cellular</title>
      <link>/privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;911cellular-llc-privacy-policy&#34;&gt;911Cellular LLC Privacy Policy&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;div id=&#34;branding&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their ‘Personally Identifiable Information’ (PII) is being used online. PII, as described in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/asburyu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/asburyu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/ashland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/ashland/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/augsburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/augsburg/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/cabrini/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/cabrini/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/campusshield/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/campusshield/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/carlow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/carlow/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/contracosta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/contracosta/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/corban/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/corban/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/desu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/desu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/dvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/dvc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/evangel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/evangel/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/gettysburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/gettysburg/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/goucher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/goucher/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/hcu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/hcu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/keuka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/keuka/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/kingscollege/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/kingscollege/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/laredo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/laredo/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/losmedanos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/losmedanos/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/maloneu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/maloneu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/marianu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/marianu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/mbu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/mbu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/mccd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/mccd/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/msc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/msc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/neiu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/neiu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/neo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/neo/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/otc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/otc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/owu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/owu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the CampusShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/utrgv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/utrgv/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the DBUShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/dbu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/dbu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the Dragon Shield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/tiffin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/tiffin/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the G Safe app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/grambling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/grambling/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the Lakeland Safe app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/lakeland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/lakeland/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the Loyno Alert app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/loyno/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/loyno/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the LSU Shield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/lsu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/lsu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the OCCC Shield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/occc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/occc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the PennWest Shield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/pennwest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/pennwest/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the Safe Dog app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/latech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/latech/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the SHU Safe app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/sacredheart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/sacredheart/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the UL Shield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/ull/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/ull/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself by downloading the WarnerShield app today!</title>
      <link>/apps/warner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apps/warner/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Violent Incidents Against Healthcare Employees</title>
      <link>/ebooks/reducing-violent-incidents-against-healthcare-employees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/ebooks/reducing-violent-incidents-against-healthcare-employees/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Request a demo</title>
      <link>/request-a-demo-thank-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/request-a-demo-thank-you/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Request A Demo of 911Cellular’s Solutions</title>
      <link>/request-a-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/request-a-demo/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Safety App | The customizable mobile safety app solution</title>
      <link>/products/mobile-safety-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/products/mobile-safety-app/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Solutions to Protect Sacred Places In Times of Uncertainty</title>
      <link>/house-of-worship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/house-of-worship/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Submission successful!</title>
      <link>/more/submission-successful-500/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/more/submission-successful-500/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take Control of Your Critical Incident Management Strategy</title>
      <link>/critical-incident-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/critical-incident-management/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tell a story</title>
      <link>/tell-a-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/tell-a-story/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thanks for your interest!</title>
      <link>/more/thanks-for-your-interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/more/thanks-for-your-interest/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Critical Cost of Violence in Healthcare</title>
      <link>/ebooks/the-critical-cost-of-violence-in-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/ebooks/the-critical-cost-of-violence-in-healthcare/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Critical Cost of Violence in Healthcare</title>
      <link>/healthcare-cost-of-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/healthcare-cost-of-violence/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultimate Guide to Campus Safety Apps</title>
      <link>/ebooks/ultimate-guide-to-campus-safety-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/ebooks/ultimate-guide-to-campus-safety-apps/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workplace Violence is ruining your organization</title>
      <link>/workplace-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/workplace-violence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-unfortunate-trend-of-workplace-violence&#34;&gt;The unfortunate trend of workplace violence&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Workplace violence has been a major concern for healthcare institutions and businesses for decades. This not-so-secret problem has been the cause of many deaths, serious injuries and time away from work&amp;hellip; all of which costs organizations millions of dollars in revenue each year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The industry most affected by workplace violence is healthcare… and it’s not even close. About 1 in 4 workplace violence incidents occur outside of the healthcare industry! That means about 75% of all workplace violence incidents are directed toward healthcare workers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;re the executive hero that will put an end to hospital violence</title>
      <link>/executive-hero/defer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/executive-hero/defer/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;re the executive hero that will put an end to hospital violence</title>
      <link>/executive-hero/start/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/executive-hero/start/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;re the executive hero that will put an end to hospital violence</title>
      <link>/executive-hero/thank-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/executive-hero/thank-you/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
