<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Geofencing on 911Cellular</title>
    <link>/tag/geofencing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Geofencing on 911Cellular</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tag/geofencing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Agile Geofencing Within Critical Communication Technology</title>
      <link>/blog/geofencing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/geofencing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-geofencing&#34;&gt;What is geofencing?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Geofencing has become a popular term and buzzword in recent years that carries with it a variety of applications in many markets. Aside from geofencing being used for marketing purposes and in the business to consumer realm, proper use of geofencing technology can be a prime differentiator for companies looking to provide critical communication services and lifesaving solutions to other organizations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But let’s back up for a second and define what a geofence actually is…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Look into Geofencing and how it can keep you safe every single day.</title>
      <link>/blog/a-look-into-geofencing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/a-look-into-geofencing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re going to be taking a look into geofencing. You may have heard of a geofence before, but never thought about how it pertains to you and your safety. A lot of apps use geofencing nowadays, and you can even use it to set reminders for yourself. If you’re heading home and need to pick up your dry-cleaning, you can set a geofencing reminder to let you know when you’re nearing the dry cleaners. This is a great resource to look at the simplicity of geofencing in your personal life: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howtogeek.com/221077/htg-explains-what-geofencing-is-and-why-you-should-be-using-it/&#34;&gt;https://www.howtogeek.com/221077/htg-explains-what-geofencing-is-and-why-you-should-be-using-it/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choosing a Mass Notification System</title>
      <link>/blog/massnotificationsystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/massnotificationsystem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mass Notification Systems are important for communities (meaning anything from school campuses to cities) and it can be overwhelming if you don’t know what you NEED in a Mass Notification System. There is a lot of information out there, and a lot of that information can seem too technical for you to understand. We would like to take some time to break down what the ideal Mass Notification System will offer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
