<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blue Light Towers on 911Cellular</title>
    <link>https://911cellular.com/tag/blue-light-towers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blue Light Towers on 911Cellular</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://911cellular.com/tag/blue-light-towers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Do blue light phones still protect students?</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/blue-light-phones/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/blue-light-phones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve visited a college campus sometime in the last decade or so, chances are you’ve seen emergency blue light phones scattered throughout campus grounds. These tall, blue pillars of safety have been a staple of campus community protection for about 30 years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature Focus: Blue Light Tower System Integration</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/blue-light-tower-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/blue-light-tower-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week’s Feature Focus, where we highlight a specific aspect of the 911Cellular Solution and find out what makes it so valuable. Today we’re focusing on integrating 911Cellular software into your existing blue light tower system.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An easily identifiable symbol of safety, blue light towers can be seen across universities, hospitals, and public spaces nationwide. The premise of the blue light tower is simple, to provide an easy way for the public to notify safety forces in the event of an emergency. Blue light towers remove the need to remember an emergency phone number, dial a phone, or locate a nearby safety officer. Activations made through a blue light tower are typically routed back to an organization’s dispatch center in the form of a phone call or pager notification.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
