<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CampusShield on 911Cellular</title>
    <link>https://911cellular.com/tag/campusshield/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CampusShield on 911Cellular</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://911cellular.com/tag/campusshield/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Ugly Reality of Sexual Violence on College Campuses</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/sexual-violence-on-college-campuses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/sexual-violence-on-college-campuses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gun violence is at an all time high in the United States, and college students today have more reasons to worry about their safety than perhaps any other generation preceding them… but most college students also have to worry about acts of sexual violence such as rape and molestation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acts of sexual violence in the United States are a lot more common than many would like to believe… especially in colleges. According to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rainn.org/statistics/campus-sexual-violence&#34;&gt;report by RAINN&lt;/a&gt; (Rape, Abuse &amp;amp; Incest National Network), 11.2% of students experience sexual assault or rape during their college years. This alarming statistic includes both graduate and undergraduate students and is not limited to just women, as men are also susceptible to such acts of violence. Moreover, 4.2% of students are stalked when they start college. Many acts of sexual violence go unreported, so the actual numbers are likely even worse.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Sure Your Campus Safety App Awareness Campaign is Successful</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/campus-safety-app-awareness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/campus-safety-app-awareness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking to upgrade safety on your college campus? A campus safety app for students, staff, faculty and visitors may be on your list of potential safety solutions for your community. If so, it’s important to understand the full scope of campus safety app awareness. Reliability, multi-functionality, and usability are all very important factors to consider when looking at different safety app products, but perhaps less obvious is the level of awareness of the app within your campus community. An app that functions perfectly will ultimately be rendered useless if the community its supposed to protect is unaware of its existence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So how can you make sure that a company with a safety app product will help you raise awareness after launch?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’ve come up with a few specific questions to ask that will give you a better understanding of the community awareness plan in place for each company you speak to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changes to Sexual Misconduct Policies on Campuses Nationwide</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/sexual-misconduct-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/sexual-misconduct-policies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Department of Education is proposing new Title IX changes that will affect sexual misconduct policies on campuses nationwide. The new changes will seek to bolster the rights of the accused, while also protecting colleges from increased liability and giving more support for victims.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A 2011 letter written by the Obama administration encouraged schools to address sexual misconduct on their own, which led many of these schools to run quasi-judicial systems in order to get to the bottom of each issue. Coupled with an expanded definition of sexual harassment, and how schools should approach dealing with it, many believed that those accused of sexual harassment didn’t stand a fighting chance and were deemed ‘guilty’ from the start.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
