<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stay Safe on 911Cellular</title>
    <link>/tag/stay-safe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stay Safe on 911Cellular</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tag/stay-safe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Can Businesses Reopen Safely?</title>
      <link>/blog/reopen-safely/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/reopen-safely/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While still in the midst of the COVID-19 pandemic many organizations are already turning their thoughts, and worries, to an unclear future. How do we collectively restart a stalled economy? What steps will it take for businesses, community organizations, universities, etc. to reopen safely? Reopening processes will need to be different for each organization and is dependent on several factors …&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt; and the subsequent &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.multistate.us/pages/covid-19-policy-tracker&#34;&gt;rules and regulations put in place by each state&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Availability of resources&lt;/strong&gt; such as masks, gloves, testing kits, etc. Access to PPE will continue to be necessary to safeguard community members and prevent a resurgence of COVID-19 cases.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infection rate.&lt;/strong&gt; Knowing the number of COVID-19 cases within your organization is just as important as knowing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/index.html&#34;&gt;number of cases in surrounding areas and states&lt;/a&gt; (i.e infection potentiality).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No matter how each of these variables affect your organization, one thing is clear, emerging from this pandemic will take collaboration and clear communication on both an organizational and individual level to reopen safely. On an organizational level this means communicating protocol changes on a consistent basis. This will require that you stay abreast of evolving current state rules/guidelines and how they apply specifically to your organization. Synthesizing this information and providing it in an easily digestible and applicable way is key to solidifying adherence. Communicating protocol changes needs to occur over a wide range of communication platforms in order to reach all members of your audience. However, communicating to your audience is not enough. Collecting community feedback is an essential component to understanding and addressing community needs. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/products/emergency-notification-system/&#34;&gt;911Cellular’s Mass Notification System&lt;/a&gt; allows organizations to send out mass notifications via 10 different platforms (call, text, email, etc.). Organizations can also choose to include community survey questions and feedback boards with their with mass notifications. This makes it effortless to collect and understand community feedback.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The COVID Safety System provides much-needed clarity for your organization</title>
      <link>/blog/covid-safety-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/covid-safety-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The rhythm of our daily life, the decisions we make, and how we operate our organizations have all been deeply affected by the COVID-19 pandemic. For many organizations, the pressure to reopen for economic and social reasons are being heavily weighed against exposure and liability risks. Business owners find themselves with decision paralysis when it comes to determining what a successful and safe reopening process looks like. In order to cut through the confusion and frustration surrounding reopening, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/&#34;&gt;911Cellular&lt;/a&gt; has created the COVID Safety System. If you’re thinking about reopening your facilities, do so safely by reducing the level of uncertainty involving COVID-19 within your organization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote Deployment During a Pandemic</title>
      <link>/blog/remote-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/remote-deployment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic has emphasized the importance of contactless delivery when it comes to grocery shopping and food delivery. But what about businesses outside of the food industry? How can businesses owners, integrators and other partners sell their products while the majority of people are still working away from the office?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many Americans are still staying home, even as some states begin to reopen, according to an analysis from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/2020/national/map-us-still-staying-home-coronavirus/?itid=hp_hp-banner-main_graphic-stayathome-1140am:homepage/story-ans&#34;&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature Focus: System Wide Multilingual Support</title>
      <link>/blog/multilingual-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/multilingual-support/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week’s Feature Focus, where we highlight a specific aspect of the 911Cellular Solution and find out what makes it so valuable. Today’s topic is multilingual support and the entirety of its reach through various products and services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is offering multilingual support so important?&lt;/strong&gt; According to the United States Census Bureau, there are over 350 languages spoken within the United States. The graph below shows the number of languages spoken based on major metropolitan areas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Predicament for Home Healthcare Workers: Uncontrolled Environments</title>
      <link>/blog/home-healthcare-workers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/home-healthcare-workers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As baby boomers age, the need for nurses and home healthcare workers will continue to climb. The Census bureau expects the number of people &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.census.gov/prod/2014pubs/p25-1140.pdf&#34;&gt;over the age of 65 to nearly double from 2012 to 2050&lt;/a&gt;. In addition to a large aging population, more people are preferring to receive medical treatment and end of life care at home, as opposed to assisted living centers or hospitals. According to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aarp.org/research/topics/community/info-2014/home-community-services-10.html&#34;&gt;2010 AARP survey&lt;/a&gt; nearly 75% of respondents (all age 45+) strongly agreed with the statement, “what I’d really like to do is stay in my current residence for as long as possible”. With more individuals falling in the 65+ age bracket and requesting healthcare at home the demand for nurses and home healthcare workers is skyrocketing. In fact, the demand for home healthcare workers is slated to increase by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bls.gov/ooh/healthcare/home-health-aides-and-personal-care-aides.htm&#34;&gt;36% between 2018 and 2028&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Addressing Community Pandemic Related Stress</title>
      <link>/blog/pandemic-related-stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/pandemic-related-stress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COVID-19 has presented everyone with a multitude of internal and external pandemic related stress points to grapple with. For some, it’s panic over the loss of a job, depression spawned from extended social isolation, or exhaustion fueled by never ending anxiety. While Netflix, Instagram and other platforms can provide much needed temporary distractions, they both fall short in addressing the root problem. Below are two common stressors that members of your community may be experiencing and some ways that you can help out:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Healthcare heroes are getting assaulted and it&#39;s costing millions</title>
      <link>/blog/violence-against-healthcare-workers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/violence-against-healthcare-workers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2020 the public is visiting hospitals and emergency departments more than ever. An unfortunate parallel increase can be seen in cases of violence against healthcare workers. What are the immediate and long term costs of workplace violence on healthcare organizations? And more importantly,  what can be done to minimize these costs and protect healthcare workers against the steady rise in workplace violence?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Calls are Overwhelming 911 Dispatch Centers</title>
      <link>/blog/covid-19-calls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/covid-19-calls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The number of cases of COVID-19 continue to rise, shelter in place ordinances have rolled out, and in some cases have been extended. Living within a pandemic has left many with questions and few reliable sources for answers. Many individuals have turned to calling 911 for answers to their questions about shelter in place orders and Coronavirus related information. Police departments and emergency dispatchers have become inundated with the severe uptick in COVID-19 calls.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Staying Safe on NYE</title>
      <link>/blog/staying-safe-on-nye/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/staying-safe-on-nye/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NYE can be such a fun holiday, but it’s important to stay safely enjoy the night. New Year’s Eve sees the highest percentage of deaths related to alcohol. Almost half of all car accidents on NYE and New Year’s Day are due to drinking and driving.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t yet, please download Uber or Lyft and familiarize yourself with the apps. You can also save a cab company’s phone number in your phone. But if you’re planning on drinking, don’t plan on driving. A $30 Uber ride is much cheaper than a DUI or worse… Do NOT drink and drive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holiday Safety Tips</title>
      <link>/blog/holiday-safety-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/holiday-safety-tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-short-guide-to-holiday-safety&#34;&gt;A Short Guide to Holiday Safety&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s safe to say that many of you out there are quite fond of the holiday season. There’s spending time with the family, delicious foods and treats (which gives me a reason to take a “brief” break from exercise) and just the sense of something magical and heart-warming in the air. However, despite the child-like wonder feeling in the atmosphere, the holiday season also holds many perils. Now, if you went out for Black Friday shopping (you’re much braver than I!) and survived, you’re half way through the dangerous part! But we still all have a month of battling Mother Nature, rival shoppers/drivers and in-laws left, so don’t let your guard down just yet!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
