<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pandemic Communication on 911Cellular</title>
    <link>/tag/pandemic-communication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pandemic Communication on 911Cellular</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tag/pandemic-communication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Addressing Community Pandemic Related Stress</title>
      <link>/blog/pandemic-related-stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/pandemic-related-stress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COVID-19 has presented everyone with a multitude of internal and external pandemic related stress points to grapple with. For some, it’s panic over the loss of a job, depression spawned from extended social isolation, or exhaustion fueled by never ending anxiety. While Netflix, Instagram and other platforms can provide much needed temporary distractions, they both fall short in addressing the root problem. Below are two common stressors that members of your community may be experiencing and some ways that you can help out:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Communicating COVID-19 Protocol to Healthcare Workers</title>
      <link>/blog/covid-19-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/covid-19-protocol/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices for Crisis Communication: Pandemic Communication Outreach</title>
      <link>/blog/pandemic-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/pandemic-communication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The rise and spread of COVID-19 has communities, businesses, and medical facilities scrambling to effectively communicate crucial information within their organizations, and to wider audiences such as patients, students, customers, etc. For many organizations this is the first time they’ve had to implement pandemic communication and mass notification practices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To assist organizations grappling with how to effectively communicate with their community in the midst of the COVID-19 pandemic, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/&#34;&gt;911Cellular&lt;/a&gt; has developed three best practices for effective pandemic communication…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
