<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community Safety on 911Cellular</title>
    <link>https://911cellular.com/tag/community-safety/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community Safety on 911Cellular</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://911cellular.com/tag/community-safety/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Emergency Response Procedures for Quick Action</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/community-emergency-response-team-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/community-emergency-response-team-training/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the essential skills and techniques for effective community emergency response team training.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Can Businesses Reopen Safely?</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/reopen-safely/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/reopen-safely/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While still in the midst of the COVID-19 pandemic many organizations are already turning their thoughts, and worries, to an unclear future. How do we collectively restart a stalled economy? What steps will it take for businesses, community organizations, universities, etc. to reopen safely? Reopening processes will need to be different for each organization and is dependent on several factors …&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt; and the subsequent &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.multistate.us/pages/covid-19-policy-tracker&#34;&gt;rules and regulations put in place by each state&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Availability of resources&lt;/strong&gt; such as masks, gloves, testing kits, etc. Access to PPE will continue to be necessary to safeguard community members and prevent a resurgence of COVID-19 cases.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infection rate.&lt;/strong&gt; Knowing the number of COVID-19 cases within your organization is just as important as knowing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/index.html&#34;&gt;number of cases in surrounding areas and states&lt;/a&gt; (i.e infection potentiality).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No matter how each of these variables affect your organization, one thing is clear, emerging from this pandemic will take collaboration and clear communication on both an organizational and individual level to reopen safely. On an organizational level this means communicating protocol changes on a consistent basis. This will require that you stay abreast of evolving current state rules/guidelines and how they apply specifically to your organization. Synthesizing this information and providing it in an easily digestible and applicable way is key to solidifying adherence. Communicating protocol changes needs to occur over a wide range of communication platforms in order to reach all members of your audience. However, communicating to your audience is not enough. Collecting community feedback is an essential component to understanding and addressing community needs. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/products/emergency-notification-system/&#34;&gt;911Cellular’s Mass Notification System&lt;/a&gt; allows organizations to send out mass notifications via 10 different platforms (call, text, email, etc.). Organizations can also choose to include community survey questions and feedback boards with their with mass notifications. This makes it effortless to collect and understand community feedback.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
