<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Silence Breakers on 911Cellular</title>
    <link>/tag/silence-breakers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Silence Breakers on 911Cellular</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tag/silence-breakers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>#MeToo, the Silence Breakers, and our Stance on Assault</title>
      <link>/blog/metoo-silence-breakers-stance-assault/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/metoo-silence-breakers-stance-assault/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Time Magazine recently just made the &amp;ldquo;Silence Breakers&amp;rdquo;; the women (and some men) who came forward to talk about sexual assault or harassment, their people of the Year. This is a significant step in the right direction as far as providing people an outlet to share their stories and feel safer coming forward when they’ve been attacked or assaulted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We talk about the Clery Act often, and we consider ourselves to be be well informed and knowledgable about the Clery Act. It is important for you to know about what the Clery Act is and how it can affect you or your child’s safety on campus. The institution’s police department or security departments are required to maintain a public log of all crimes reported to them, or those of which they are made aware. These public logs should be made available on college websites or by the request of the student or the parent(s) of the student. No student should ever feel afraid to tell campus police or trusted officials about a rape that occurred or an assault that took place. If a movement like #MeToo can make students feel safer and give them the ability to talk about something that happened to them, then we support that movement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
