<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Preventing School Shootings on 911Cellular</title>
    <link>/tag/preventing-school-shootings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Preventing School Shootings on 911Cellular</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tag/preventing-school-shootings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Alyssa&#39;s Law Enhances School Security Systems</title>
      <link>/blog/how-alyssas-law-enhances-school-security-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/how-alyssas-law-enhances-school-security-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an era where the safety of students is paramount, schools across the United States are increasingly focused on enhancing their security systems. One of the most significant legislative measures driving this change is &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/alyssas-law/&#34;&gt;Alyssa&amp;rsquo;s Law&lt;/a&gt;, which has been enacted in several states to improve emergency response times and ensure the &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/industries/k12schools/&#34;&gt;safety of students&lt;/a&gt; during critical incidents. But what exactly does Alyssa&amp;rsquo;s Law entail, and how does it enhance school security systems? This blog explores the impact of Alyssa&amp;rsquo;s Law on school security and what it means for schools striving to keep their students safe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empowering School Safety: Alyssa&#39;s Law Explained</title>
      <link>/blog/alyssas-law-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/alyssas-law-explained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover how &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/alyssas-law/&#34;&gt;Alyssa&amp;rsquo;s Law&lt;/a&gt; is revolutionizing school safety measures and empowering educators, students, and parents alike.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preventing School Shootings: Effective Strategies for Safety</title>
      <link>/blog/how-to-prevent-school-shootings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/how-to-prevent-school-shootings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover effective strategies to prevent school shootings and ensure the safety of students and staff.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ensuring School Safety: A Comprehensive Guide</title>
      <link>/blog/ensuring-school-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/ensuring-school-safety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover effective strategies and measures to ensure the safety of students and staff in schools.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crisis Management in K-12 Schools: Best Practices and Case Studies</title>
      <link>/blog/crisis-management-in-k-12-schools-best-practices-and-case-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/crisis-management-in-k-12-schools-best-practices-and-case-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s world, ensuring the safety and security of students and staff in K-12 schools is a top priority. Schools must be prepared to respond swiftly and effectively to a wide range of crises, from natural disasters to security threats. This calls for a comprehensive approach to crisis management, one that incorporates best practices and draws from real-life case studies. In this blog, we will explore the key elements of crisis management in K-12 schools and showcase some case studies that highlight successful strategies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>School Shooting in Uvalde, Texas</title>
      <link>/blog/school-shooting-uvalde-texas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/school-shooting-uvalde-texas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On May 24th, a gunman entered an elementary school in Uvalde, Texas with an AR-15 and a handgun. He then proceeded to kill 21 children and adults, while also critically injuring even more, making this the deadliest school shooting in the United States since the Sandy Hook Elementary School shooting in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our hearts go out to the victims, their families, and the local community in Uvalde.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gun Violence in Schools: Does it Cause Lasting Damage?</title>
      <link>/blog/school-gun-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/school-gun-violence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Does gun violence cause lasting physical and psychological damage to America’s youth? Even in recent years with the COVID-19 pandemic, there has been a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.psu.edu/news/research/story/us-gun-violence-increased-30-percent-during-covid-19-pandemic/&#34;&gt;significant increase&lt;/a&gt; in the amount of gun violence in American schools, according to researchers at Penn State. Besides the obvious immediate effects on schoolchildren, there may be some long-lasting damage to consider.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What long-term mental and physical effects can be expected in young students who have previously experienced a violent event in their schools?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arkansas school shooting has students afraid to return</title>
      <link>/blog/arkansas-school-shooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/arkansas-school-shooting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Citizens of Pine Bluff, Arkansas are still recovering from the devastating Arkansas school shooting that took place on Monday, March 1st at Watson Chapel Junior High School. The shooting resulted in the death of a 15-year-old boy who was in critical condition before passing away days later. The suspected gunman is a 15-year-old classmate of the victim’s and was found hiding behind a house near the school. The shooting appears to be a ‘targeted incident’ according to local police and the suspect’s motives are still under investigation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Becoming Alyssa’s Law Compliant 101</title>
      <link>/blog/alyssas-law-compliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/alyssas-law-compliance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On February 14, 2018, a gunman opened fire at Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School in Parkland, Florida, killing 17 people. One of the victims of this horrific tragedy was Alyssa Alhadeff, a 14 year old talented writer and soccer player. In the wake of her daughter’s death, Lori Alhadeff, Alyssa’s mother, took action to prevent future school violence. This is how Alyssa’s law was created.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Alyssa’s  Law?&lt;/strong&gt; Alyssa’s Law is critical legislation which addresses law enforcement response time when a life-threatening emergency occurs. The law calls for the installation of silent panic alarms that are directly linked to law enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>School Shooting Lessons Learned: Noblesville West Middle School</title>
      <link>/blog/school-shooting-lessons-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/school-shooting-lessons-learned/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, Indiana county leaders gathered to attend the Indiana Association of County Commissioners in an effort to discuss the lessons learned from the Noblesville West Middle School Shooting that took place earlier this year. On May 25th, 2018, a 13-year old student and her teacher were shot during the incident before the suspect was wrestled to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the first time since the shooting happened, commissioners had the chance to hear directly from the people in Hamilton County who responded to the scene that day. The main takeaway: being prepared makes a big difference in these types of situations. Before the time of the shooting, Hamilton County’s Emergency Management team hosted multiple active shooter training drills with local police, fire and medical personnel in specific scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will School Safety Politics Affect Young Voter Turnout?</title>
      <link>/blog/voting-school-safety-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/voting-school-safety-politics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Young voters in America have historically shown a low percentage of voting participation, but this year… school safety politics might change that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the last 20 years, no more than 20 percent of those age 18 to 24 have gone to the polls to voice their opinions during a midterm election. This year could be different.. according to an Education Week study which surveyed the youngest eligible voters, nearly two-thirds of respondents said they plan to vote this year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Florida Shootings Spark Talk of Proactive Safety Measures</title>
      <link>/blog/florida-shootings-proactive-safety-measures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/florida-shootings-proactive-safety-measures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Residents, students and employees within the state of Florida can agree on one thing… it’s important to start taking proactive safety measures in order to halt the all too common mass shooting events that keep happening in the southern state. The discussion diverges from there, with several viewpoints on both sides of the political spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Florida’s recent history with mass shootings is appalling… in 2016, 49 were killed at the Pulse nightclub in Orlando. In 2017, five died in the Fort Lauderdale airport shooting. And so far in 2018, two more shootings on Florida soil… 17 were killed in the Parkland shooting at Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School, and three died, including the gunman, at the most recent shooting that took place at a Madden video game tournament in Jacksonville.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>School Shootings: Can we prevent them?</title>
      <link>/blog/school-shootings-can-we-prevent-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/school-shootings-can-we-prevent-them/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;School shootings are becoming increasingly more common, and we find ourselves asking “Can we stop school shootings from happening?”  There is no way to ensure school shooting prevention, but we would like to share some information that may be useful when it comes to creating a school and home environment that may be beneficial to putting an end to some of the violence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Strength-based support. This is a phrase you may have seen before, and we’ll explain exactly what it means. All too often, active school shooters feel alienated and alone. They feel like outcasts. If you can identify a student that is having a hard time in mainstream classes, but may have great artistic ability or they really enjoy coding in computer class, you can offer them strength-based support. Find those kids and offer them incentives to strengthen their areas of expertise. Corrective teaching is great for most students; helping them identify their weaknesses and working to correct those issues. But children who suffer tremendous isolation will only feel MORE isolated in that type of learning environment. By nurturing students that feel like they’re outcasts, we may be able to prevent school shootings.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Schools can offer guidance from a Relationship Officer. These can be guidance counselors, teachers, or other facility members that offer support to students who’s home lives may not have strong adult role models. Schools can also employ a Relationship Officer. These are different from counselors. Their goals are to connect with students and offer them a healthy adult/student relationship that will open the doors to trust and acceptance.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you see something, report it. Whether it’s bullying, signs of abuse, signs of malnourishment, or anything that’s way outside the norm. Most active school shooters acted violently because of extreme bullying or deep feelings of isolation. We can prevent school shootings by making sure all students feel cared for. A lot of schools are overwhelmed and it’s hard to report every single incident, but it’s the one way to ensure that everything is being documented and if there are enough incidents with one student, you will be able to determine that there is a pattern. Counties are also juggling more work than most can handle, but creating a paper trail WILL help in the long run. Even if you’re the only one that sees the paper trail, at least you’ll be able to easily identify a student that could be a risk or at risk.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Talk to your children about mental health, and let them know that there is no stigma involved with needed to talk to someone. We would much rather see a large influx of children talking to therapists as opposed to children shooting up schools. If you think your own child may need help, there is no shame in getting them into therapy. You haven’t failed as a parent; you are actually doing them a favor by getting them the help they need. We know you would rather see your child get help and potentially stop them from becoming an active school shooter. Most counties and cities even offer free services.  Children Services would much rather help you get the resources you need instead of taking a child from your home or worse, putting your child into a detention center. Do not be afraid to contact Children Services or your child’s school if you feel there are psychological issues. You might be surprised to learn that Children Services also offers support groups for parents, and you as a parent may benefit from them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Keeping our children safe should be our number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
