<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncategorized on 911Cellular</title>
    <link>/tag/uncategorized/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uncategorized on 911Cellular</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tag/uncategorized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Are your emergency messages reaching the right people?</title>
      <link>/blog/emergency-messages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/emergency-messages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are the pros and cons of some of the emergency messages platforms available today, as well as suggestions on how to make your emergency alert program more effective. When an emergency happens, campus officials must be able to quickly disseminate critical information so their community members can take appropriate actions to protect themselves and the individuals in their care. How a person responds can vary, depending on their situation and location. They might need to shelter in place, lock down, evacuate or some other action.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, before anyone can respond to an alert, they must first be able to see, hear or read the announcement. Unfortunately, no one type of technology can reach everyone in a campus community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SMS text messaging systems are an excellent way to reach a large number of community members, but these systems generally require a person to register in order to receive notifications. What about people who aren’t registered, such as visitors? What about students in class who have turned off their phones to take a test? What about those who don’t have a mobile phone? How will campus administrators be able to reach these individuals?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Loudspeakers and other types of audible announcements are another effective way of disseminating emergency messages, especially to visitors or others on campus who are not registered for your organization’s SMS text alert system. But what about the individuals on your campus who are hearing-impaired or wearing headphones and can’t hear the emergency announcement?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Digital displays and pop-up computer messages are another excellent option, especially for campuses that have a lot of visitors or individuals who are hard of hearing, or if the loudspeakers aren’t powerful enough for audible announcements to be heard in a loud environment such as a school hallway filled with students. But what about individuals who are sight-impaired? How can campus officials reach them during a crisis?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2018: K-12 School Gun Violence Review For The Year</title>
      <link>/blog/k-12-school-gun-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/k-12-school-gun-violence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chds.us/ssdb/&#34;&gt;study from the US Naval Postgraduate School&lt;/a&gt;, 2018 was a particularly bad year for K-12 school gun violence. There were 94 K-12 school gun violence incidents this year, the most since 1970 (which is where the data starts). In 2006, there were 59 (the next highest on record).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When looking at the data from the perspective of lives lost, 2018 was also the worst year on record. So far, 55 people have died (including the shooter) this year in K-12 school gun violence incidents. The next highest death toll by year was in 1993 (40).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>School Shooting Lessons Learned: Noblesville West Middle School</title>
      <link>/blog/school-shooting-lessons-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/school-shooting-lessons-learned/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, Indiana county leaders gathered to attend the Indiana Association of County Commissioners in an effort to discuss the lessons learned from the Noblesville West Middle School Shooting that took place earlier this year. On May 25th, 2018, a 13-year old student and her teacher were shot during the incident before the suspect was wrestled to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the first time since the shooting happened, commissioners had the chance to hear directly from the people in Hamilton County who responded to the scene that day. The main takeaway: being prepared makes a big difference in these types of situations. Before the time of the shooting, Hamilton County’s Emergency Management team hosted multiple active shooter training drills with local police, fire and medical personnel in specific scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
