<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Public Safety on 911Cellular</title>
    <link>/tag/public-safety/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Public Safety on 911Cellular</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tag/public-safety/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Incident Command System (ICS): A Critical Tool for Crisis Management</title>
      <link>/blog/understanding-the-incident-command-system-ics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/understanding-the-incident-command-system-ics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced world, where unforeseen events can disrupt operations in an instant, businesses and organizations must be prepared to respond effectively to emergencies. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s a natural disaster, a security threat, or a critical incident within your organization, having a structured and efficient response plan is essential. This is where the &lt;strong&gt;Incident Command System (ICS)&lt;/strong&gt; comes into play.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How a Mass Notification System Can Save Lives</title>
      <link>/blog/how-a-mass-notification-system-can-save-lives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/how-a-mass-notification-system-can-save-lives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the power and importance of a mass notification system in emergency situations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Staff Training for Optimal Response to Critical Incidents</title>
      <link>/blog/enhancing-staff-training-for-optimal-response-to-critical-incidents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/enhancing-staff-training-for-optimal-response-to-critical-incidents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to critical incident management, preparedness is the cornerstone of effective response. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s a healthcare facility, an educational institution, or any other B2B setting, the ability of staff members to respond swiftly and decisively during emergencies can make the difference between a manageable situation and a catastrophe. This is where staff training steps onto the stage as a vital component of a comprehensive critical incident management strategy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Can Businesses Reopen Safely?</title>
      <link>/blog/reopen-safely/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/reopen-safely/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While still in the midst of the COVID-19 pandemic many organizations are already turning their thoughts, and worries, to an unclear future. How do we collectively restart a stalled economy? What steps will it take for businesses, community organizations, universities, etc. to reopen safely? Reopening processes will need to be different for each organization and is dependent on several factors …&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt; and the subsequent &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.multistate.us/pages/covid-19-policy-tracker&#34;&gt;rules and regulations put in place by each state&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Availability of resources&lt;/strong&gt; such as masks, gloves, testing kits, etc. Access to PPE will continue to be necessary to safeguard community members and prevent a resurgence of COVID-19 cases.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infection rate.&lt;/strong&gt; Knowing the number of COVID-19 cases within your organization is just as important as knowing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/index.html&#34;&gt;number of cases in surrounding areas and states&lt;/a&gt; (i.e infection potentiality).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No matter how each of these variables affect your organization, one thing is clear, emerging from this pandemic will take collaboration and clear communication on both an organizational and individual level to reopen safely. On an organizational level this means communicating protocol changes on a consistent basis. This will require that you stay abreast of evolving current state rules/guidelines and how they apply specifically to your organization. Synthesizing this information and providing it in an easily digestible and applicable way is key to solidifying adherence. Communicating protocol changes needs to occur over a wide range of communication platforms in order to reach all members of your audience. However, communicating to your audience is not enough. Collecting community feedback is an essential component to understanding and addressing community needs. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/products/emergency-notification-system/&#34;&gt;911Cellular’s Mass Notification System&lt;/a&gt; allows organizations to send out mass notifications via 10 different platforms (call, text, email, etc.). Organizations can also choose to include community survey questions and feedback boards with their with mass notifications. This makes it effortless to collect and understand community feedback.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The next generation emergency response team is not what you think</title>
      <link>/blog/employee-safety-active-shooters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/employee-safety-active-shooters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Employee safety, especially active shooter situations, was the topic of conversation at the American Society of Safety Professionals (ASSP) Safety 2018 conference recently held in San Antonio, Texas. During this forum attendees were able to hear from FBI agents, law enforcement professionals and other key groups with insight into some best practices to promote employee safety during an active shooter situation at the workplace.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The general tone of the forum was that prevention is not always possible. This has become an unfortunate reality; and that making plans to safeguard employee safety for the largest possible number of people is key to minimizing casualties.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are your emergency messages reaching the right people?</title>
      <link>/blog/emergency-messages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/emergency-messages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are the pros and cons of some of the emergency messages platforms available today, as well as suggestions on how to make your emergency alert program more effective. When an emergency happens, campus officials must be able to quickly disseminate critical information so their community members can take appropriate actions to protect themselves and the individuals in their care. How a person responds can vary, depending on their situation and location. They might need to shelter in place, lock down, evacuate or some other action.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, before anyone can respond to an alert, they must first be able to see, hear or read the announcement. Unfortunately, no one type of technology can reach everyone in a campus community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SMS text messaging systems are an excellent way to reach a large number of community members, but these systems generally require a person to register in order to receive notifications. What about people who aren’t registered, such as visitors? What about students in class who have turned off their phones to take a test? What about those who don’t have a mobile phone? How will campus administrators be able to reach these individuals?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Loudspeakers and other types of audible announcements are another effective way of disseminating emergency messages, especially to visitors or others on campus who are not registered for your organization’s SMS text alert system. But what about the individuals on your campus who are hearing-impaired or wearing headphones and can’t hear the emergency announcement?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Digital displays and pop-up computer messages are another excellent option, especially for campuses that have a lot of visitors or individuals who are hard of hearing, or if the loudspeakers aren’t powerful enough for audible announcements to be heard in a loud environment such as a school hallway filled with students. But what about individuals who are sight-impaired? How can campus officials reach them during a crisis?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature Focus: COVID Tools, Submit Tip &amp; Resource Tile</title>
      <link>/blog/covid-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/covid-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week’s Feature Focus, where we highlight a specific aspect of the 911Cellular Solution and find out what makes it so valuable. Today’s topic is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/products/mobile-safety-app/&#34;&gt;Mobile Safety App&lt;/a&gt; features that can assist your organization in reopening, remaining open safely, and preventing the spread of COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/blog/911Cellular-Submit-Tip-COVID-Feature.jpg.webp&#34; alt=&#34;=Covid safety app&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Submit Tip feature&lt;/strong&gt; shines for its ability to be customized and molded to fit your organization’s needs. Administrators can create tip categories such as ‘social distancing violation’, ‘unsafe public gathering’, etc. App users can easily and discreetly notify health and safety forces anonymously as well as include helpful pictures and videos. In turn, safety forces have the option to start a conversation with the tip submitter, even if the tip submitter chose to remain anonymous. Additionally, the organization’s Administrators can be proactive in encouraging use of the feature by enabling a ‘See Something, Say Something’ campaign. This campaign will automatically send push notifications to a small portion of your community each day, asking them a question such as ‘have you seen any mask violations lately?’. When an app user clicks into the push notification, they will be taken directly to the Submit Tip feature.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Becoming Alyssa’s Law Compliant 101</title>
      <link>/blog/alyssas-law-compliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/alyssas-law-compliance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On February 14, 2018, a gunman opened fire at Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School in Parkland, Florida, killing 17 people. One of the victims of this horrific tragedy was Alyssa Alhadeff, a 14 year old talented writer and soccer player. In the wake of her daughter’s death, Lori Alhadeff, Alyssa’s mother, took action to prevent future school violence. This is how Alyssa’s law was created.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Alyssa’s  Law?&lt;/strong&gt; Alyssa’s Law is critical legislation which addresses law enforcement response time when a life-threatening emergency occurs. The law calls for the installation of silent panic alarms that are directly linked to law enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The COVID Safety System provides much-needed clarity for your organization</title>
      <link>/blog/covid-safety-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/covid-safety-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The rhythm of our daily life, the decisions we make, and how we operate our organizations have all been deeply affected by the COVID-19 pandemic. For many organizations, the pressure to reopen for economic and social reasons are being heavily weighed against exposure and liability risks. Business owners find themselves with decision paralysis when it comes to determining what a successful and safe reopening process looks like. In order to cut through the confusion and frustration surrounding reopening, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/&#34;&gt;911Cellular&lt;/a&gt; has created the COVID Safety System. If you’re thinking about reopening your facilities, do so safely by reducing the level of uncertainty involving COVID-19 within your organization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature Focus: Blue Light Tower System Integration</title>
      <link>/blog/blue-light-tower-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/blue-light-tower-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week’s Feature Focus, where we highlight a specific aspect of the 911Cellular Solution and find out what makes it so valuable. Today we’re focusing on integrating 911Cellular software into your existing blue light tower system.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An easily identifiable symbol of safety, blue light towers can be seen across universities, hospitals, and public spaces nationwide. The premise of the blue light tower is simple, to provide an easy way for the public to notify safety forces in the event of an emergency. Blue light towers remove the need to remember an emergency phone number, dial a phone, or locate a nearby safety officer. Activations made through a blue light tower are typically routed back to an organization’s dispatch center in the form of a phone call or pager notification.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Predicament for Home Healthcare Workers: Uncontrolled Environments</title>
      <link>/blog/home-healthcare-workers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/home-healthcare-workers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As baby boomers age, the need for nurses and home healthcare workers will continue to climb. The Census bureau expects the number of people &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.census.gov/prod/2014pubs/p25-1140.pdf&#34;&gt;over the age of 65 to nearly double from 2012 to 2050&lt;/a&gt;. In addition to a large aging population, more people are preferring to receive medical treatment and end of life care at home, as opposed to assisted living centers or hospitals. According to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aarp.org/research/topics/community/info-2014/home-community-services-10.html&#34;&gt;2010 AARP survey&lt;/a&gt; nearly 75% of respondents (all age 45+) strongly agreed with the statement, “what I’d really like to do is stay in my current residence for as long as possible”. With more individuals falling in the 65+ age bracket and requesting healthcare at home the demand for nurses and home healthcare workers is skyrocketing. In fact, the demand for home healthcare workers is slated to increase by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bls.gov/ooh/healthcare/home-health-aides-and-personal-care-aides.htm&#34;&gt;36% between 2018 and 2028&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 things your organization should do to prepare for the upcoming climate crisis</title>
      <link>/blog/preempt-emergencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/preempt-emergencies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No organization can fully prepare for every possible scenario, but there are ways to preempt emergencies that can help every organization, regardless of size. Communication remains a key piece to emergency management and preparedness, so we’ve outlined a few ways to get ahead of the curve when it comes to protecting your organization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Addressing Community Pandemic Related Stress</title>
      <link>/blog/pandemic-related-stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/pandemic-related-stress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COVID-19 has presented everyone with a multitude of internal and external pandemic related stress points to grapple with. For some, it’s panic over the loss of a job, depression spawned from extended social isolation, or exhaustion fueled by never ending anxiety. While Netflix, Instagram and other platforms can provide much needed temporary distractions, they both fall short in addressing the root problem. Below are two common stressors that members of your community may be experiencing and some ways that you can help out:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Calls are Overwhelming 911 Dispatch Centers</title>
      <link>/blog/covid-19-calls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/covid-19-calls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The number of cases of COVID-19 continue to rise, shelter in place ordinances have rolled out, and in some cases have been extended. Living within a pandemic has left many with questions and few reliable sources for answers. Many individuals have turned to calling 911 for answers to their questions about shelter in place orders and Coronavirus related information. Police departments and emergency dispatchers have become inundated with the severe uptick in COVID-19 calls.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices for Crisis Communication: Pandemic Communication Outreach</title>
      <link>/blog/pandemic-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/pandemic-communication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The rise and spread of COVID-19 has communities, businesses, and medical facilities scrambling to effectively communicate crucial information within their organizations, and to wider audiences such as patients, students, customers, etc. For many organizations this is the first time they’ve had to implement pandemic communication and mass notification practices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To assist organizations grappling with how to effectively communicate with their community in the midst of the COVID-19 pandemic, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/&#34;&gt;911Cellular&lt;/a&gt; has developed three best practices for effective pandemic communication…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Comprehensive Safety Solution: Made to Fit Your Organization</title>
      <link>/blog/comprehensive-safety-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/comprehensive-safety-solution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot the 911Cellular solution can do for almost any organization, regardless of size or industry… and for that it can be accurately labelled the comprehensive safety solution. But perhaps the most beneficial aspect of the 911Cellular solution is its ability to fit within your organization like a glove.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Feature Focus: App Configuration Elevating Community Safety</title>
      <link>/blog/app-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/app-configuration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this Feature Focus, we’ll touch on App Configuration, which is an incredibly unique and fun feature that allows Administrators to quickly customize their Mobile Safety App in a variety of ways… all completed easily from the 911Cellular Portal. One of the most attractive elements of this feature is that this customization can happen for all Mobile Safety App accounts! This means that even those who did not purchase a white label Mobile Safety App (custom name and icon) can take advantage of these customization tools!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature Focus: HIPS (Hyper-Accurate Indoor Positioning System)</title>
      <link>/blog/hyper-accurate-indoor-positioning-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/hyper-accurate-indoor-positioning-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this Feature Focus, we will dip our toes into the vast ocean of indoor positioning system technology, and why 911Cellular’s HIPS (Hyper-Accurate Indoor Positioning System) is transforming the emergency communications landscape.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bracing For Severe Weather in 2019</title>
      <link>/blog/severe-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/severe-weather/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last two years were quite stressful for large portions of the United States living in areas prone to natural disasters and severe weather. In 2018, the US incurred a record high of $33.79 billion in damages due to 15 storms, eight hurricanes and two major tornadoes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the United States is still under the threat of catastrophic hurricanes and storms, it is slowly becoming essential that various institutions take advantage of severe weather alert systems. 2019 is likely to follow in the footsteps of 2018, bringing about a slew of storms and hurricanes of varying strengths.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protesters Focus on Effort to Occupy University Police Offices</title>
      <link>/blog/protesters-occupy-university-police/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/protesters-occupy-university-police/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly 3 months ago, Jason Washington, a 45 year old Navy veteran, was shot and killed by Portland State University police officers after being told by police to drop his friend’s gun during a street fight. Jason was trying to de-escalate the fight, according to witnesses and body cam footage, that started when his friend, Jeremy Wilkinson, used a racial slur and threw a stranger’s phone.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On Monday, students and protesters made demands as their rallies turned into an effort to occupy university police offices. Protesters say they will occupy the space until their demands are met: the immediate disarmament of PSU police officers, the firing of the officers involved in the case, and a permanent memorial to Jason Washington erected on campus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Florida Shootings Spark Talk of Proactive Safety Measures</title>
      <link>/blog/florida-shootings-proactive-safety-measures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/florida-shootings-proactive-safety-measures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Residents, students and employees within the state of Florida can agree on one thing… it’s important to start taking proactive safety measures in order to halt the all too common mass shooting events that keep happening in the southern state. The discussion diverges from there, with several viewpoints on both sides of the political spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Florida’s recent history with mass shootings is appalling… in 2016, 49 were killed at the Pulse nightclub in Orlando. In 2017, five died in the Fort Lauderdale airport shooting. And so far in 2018, two more shootings on Florida soil… 17 were killed in the Parkland shooting at Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School, and three died, including the gunman, at the most recent shooting that took place at a Madden video game tournament in Jacksonville.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wildfires &amp; Communication</title>
      <link>/blog/wildfire-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/wildfire-communication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Communication during wildfires is crucial.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s been a devastating wildfire season so far in 2018. West coast residents have been exposed to 16 major wildfires that have burned more than 300,000 acres. The size of these wildfires are particularly troubling, as are their proximity to inhabited communities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many residents are seeing their homes burn despite taking the recommended precautions (creating defensible space and using non-flammable building materials). In some cases, the flame wall can ignite homes from half a mile away, with embers flying above rivers and roads to set the homes ablaze.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Event Safety Relevant Now More Than Ever</title>
      <link>/blog/event-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/event-safety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the World Cup starting this week, most of us are thinking about the matches, festivities and glory. But for those who are tasked with providing event safety, the soccer is likely near the back of their minds. Event safety can be extremely complicated, especially for an event that spans a full month and covers an entire county (in this case, a country that is almost an entire continent). Event safety complications arise from both inside and outside the venues. Especially in soccer, where fans are notorious for their extra-curricular fights (see the movie Green Street Hooligans for more insight).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Safety Solutions for Cities</title>
      <link>/blog/safety-solutions-for-cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/safety-solutions-for-cities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are so many safety solutions for cities that are not always well known to the public, and we’d like to help share some information to keep you safe in your hometown.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Keeping a city safe is like building a house. It needs to start with a good foundation, then it requires a lot of work and the proper tools. You can’t build a house with just a hammer, no matter how good that hammer is. We offer tools that assist police departments and citizens. Safety solutions for cities can come in the form of app systems like ours, where we offer a security system in your pocket. 911Cellular offers &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/app-systems/&#34;&gt;PublicShield&lt;/a&gt;, which gives you the ability to receive mass notifications from city officials, gives you direct access to police with an app that can send out your exact location to emergency personnel in case of an emergency, and gives you the ability to share tips or suspicious activity (along with pictures or video) anonymously to your police department.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hospitals aren&#39;t safe places for these individuals</title>
      <link>/blog/hospital-safety-and-eliminating-workplace-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/hospital-safety-and-eliminating-workplace-violence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hospital safety isn’t something the average person thinks about. Hospitals are where we go for emergencies, surgeries, births, and general ailments. As a patient of hospitals, we think of the staff as our care providers. What most people don’t know is that between 2011 and 2013, nearly 75% of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fiercehealthcare.com/healthcare/workplace-violence-healthcare-underreported-and-often-ignored&#34;&gt;workplace assaults&lt;/a&gt; took place in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fiercehealthcare.com/finance/violence-cost-hospitals-2-7b-2016-aha-report-finds&#34;&gt;healthcare settings&lt;/a&gt;. While we are getting treated for our health issues, the staff in our hospitals are getting assaulted by their patients or the patient’s family members/friends. This is a very serious issue, and one that we don’t hear about often enough.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>National School Walkout and School Safety</title>
      <link>/blog/national-school-walkout-school-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/national-school-walkout-school-safety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, we ran some polls on our social media accounts and asked our readers if they felt that the National School Walkouts would help change gun laws and help with school safety. Instead of answering “yes” or “no”, most people answered “hopefully”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No matter what your stance is on gun laws and gun control, I think most people will agree that there needs to be some changes made within the schools to keep our students safe. We have a gun violence issue, and it needs to be dealt with, As I’m writing this, i’m watching the news about yet another school shooting in Maryland. This is unacceptable. We, the adults that are able to vote and have our voices heard, must stand up for our children and be advocates for their safety and well being.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>911Cellular is named one of the Top Government Tech Solution Providers of 2018</title>
      <link>/blog/911cellular-is-named-one-of-the-top-government-tech-solution-providers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/911cellular-is-named-one-of-the-top-government-tech-solution-providers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;911Cellular is named one of the Top Government Tech Solution Providers of 2018 in CIO Applications Magazine. CIO Magazine sat down with Chad Salahshour, the President and CEO of 911Cellular, to talk about how 911Cellular came to fruition. Chad is still actively involved with a local police department, and it’s because of his law enforcement background that he created and started implementing our lifesaving technology across the country. 911Cellular works with dispatchers and smartphone users to open up the lines of emergency communication and to pinpoint your location during an emergency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>School Shootings: Can we prevent them?</title>
      <link>/blog/school-shootings-can-we-prevent-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/school-shootings-can-we-prevent-them/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;School shootings are becoming increasingly more common, and we find ourselves asking “Can we stop school shootings from happening?”  There is no way to ensure school shooting prevention, but we would like to share some information that may be useful when it comes to creating a school and home environment that may be beneficial to putting an end to some of the violence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Strength-based support. This is a phrase you may have seen before, and we’ll explain exactly what it means. All too often, active school shooters feel alienated and alone. They feel like outcasts. If you can identify a student that is having a hard time in mainstream classes, but may have great artistic ability or they really enjoy coding in computer class, you can offer them strength-based support. Find those kids and offer them incentives to strengthen their areas of expertise. Corrective teaching is great for most students; helping them identify their weaknesses and working to correct those issues. But children who suffer tremendous isolation will only feel MORE isolated in that type of learning environment. By nurturing students that feel like they’re outcasts, we may be able to prevent school shootings.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Schools can offer guidance from a Relationship Officer. These can be guidance counselors, teachers, or other facility members that offer support to students who’s home lives may not have strong adult role models. Schools can also employ a Relationship Officer. These are different from counselors. Their goals are to connect with students and offer them a healthy adult/student relationship that will open the doors to trust and acceptance.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you see something, report it. Whether it’s bullying, signs of abuse, signs of malnourishment, or anything that’s way outside the norm. Most active school shooters acted violently because of extreme bullying or deep feelings of isolation. We can prevent school shootings by making sure all students feel cared for. A lot of schools are overwhelmed and it’s hard to report every single incident, but it’s the one way to ensure that everything is being documented and if there are enough incidents with one student, you will be able to determine that there is a pattern. Counties are also juggling more work than most can handle, but creating a paper trail WILL help in the long run. Even if you’re the only one that sees the paper trail, at least you’ll be able to easily identify a student that could be a risk or at risk.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Talk to your children about mental health, and let them know that there is no stigma involved with needed to talk to someone. We would much rather see a large influx of children talking to therapists as opposed to children shooting up schools. If you think your own child may need help, there is no shame in getting them into therapy. You haven’t failed as a parent; you are actually doing them a favor by getting them the help they need. We know you would rather see your child get help and potentially stop them from becoming an active school shooter. Most counties and cities even offer free services.  Children Services would much rather help you get the resources you need instead of taking a child from your home or worse, putting your child into a detention center. Do not be afraid to contact Children Services or your child’s school if you feel there are psychological issues. You might be surprised to learn that Children Services also offers support groups for parents, and you as a parent may benefit from them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Keeping our children safe should be our number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choosing a Mass Notification System</title>
      <link>/blog/massnotificationsystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/massnotificationsystem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mass Notification Systems are important for communities (meaning anything from school campuses to cities) and it can be overwhelming if you don’t know what you NEED in a Mass Notification System. There is a lot of information out there, and a lot of that information can seem too technical for you to understand. We would like to take some time to break down what the ideal Mass Notification System will offer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#MeToo, the Silence Breakers, and our Stance on Assault</title>
      <link>/blog/metoo-silence-breakers-stance-assault/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/metoo-silence-breakers-stance-assault/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Time Magazine recently just made the &amp;ldquo;Silence Breakers&amp;rdquo;; the women (and some men) who came forward to talk about sexual assault or harassment, their people of the Year. This is a significant step in the right direction as far as providing people an outlet to share their stories and feel safer coming forward when they’ve been attacked or assaulted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We talk about the Clery Act often, and we consider ourselves to be be well informed and knowledgable about the Clery Act. It is important for you to know about what the Clery Act is and how it can affect you or your child’s safety on campus. The institution’s police department or security departments are required to maintain a public log of all crimes reported to them, or those of which they are made aware. These public logs should be made available on college websites or by the request of the student or the parent(s) of the student. No student should ever feel afraid to tell campus police or trusted officials about a rape that occurred or an assault that took place. If a movement like #MeToo can make students feel safer and give them the ability to talk about something that happened to them, then we support that movement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Guide to Holiday Safety</title>
      <link>/blog/holiday-safety-tips-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/holiday-safety-tips-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The holidays are always fun. Shopping for gifts for your loved ones, finding great deals online, and going on holiday vacations are just a few of the things that most of us look forward to. But unfortunately, holidays are also a time where holiday safety issues arise, but we very rarely do we think about holiday safety and it’s importance. So we wanted to give you holiday safety tips that you can use to safeguard yourself, your home, and your loved ones. These holiday safety tips are things that you can practice all of the time; not just during the holidays.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
