<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EducationShield on 911Cellular</title>
    <link>/tag/educationshield/</link>
    <description>Recent content in EducationShield on 911Cellular</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tag/educationshield/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2018: K-12 School Gun Violence Review For The Year</title>
      <link>/blog/k-12-school-gun-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/k-12-school-gun-violence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chds.us/ssdb/&#34;&gt;study from the US Naval Postgraduate School&lt;/a&gt;, 2018 was a particularly bad year for K-12 school gun violence. There were 94 K-12 school gun violence incidents this year, the most since 1970 (which is where the data starts). In 2006, there were 59 (the next highest on record).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When looking at the data from the perspective of lives lost, 2018 was also the worst year on record. So far, 55 people have died (including the shooter) this year in K-12 school gun violence incidents. The next highest death toll by year was in 1993 (40).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>School Shooting Lessons Learned: Noblesville West Middle School</title>
      <link>/blog/school-shooting-lessons-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/school-shooting-lessons-learned/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, Indiana county leaders gathered to attend the Indiana Association of County Commissioners in an effort to discuss the lessons learned from the Noblesville West Middle School Shooting that took place earlier this year. On May 25th, 2018, a 13-year old student and her teacher were shot during the incident before the suspect was wrestled to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the first time since the shooting happened, commissioners had the chance to hear directly from the people in Hamilton County who responded to the scene that day. The main takeaway: being prepared makes a big difference in these types of situations. Before the time of the shooting, Hamilton County’s Emergency Management team hosted multiple active shooter training drills with local police, fire and medical personnel in specific scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Our Schools Safe While Providing Inclusive School Safety Solutions</title>
      <link>/blog/inclusive-school-safety-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/inclusive-school-safety-solutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amidst all the shouting about protecting our students at school, are we ready to provide inclusive school safety solutions? This past year has been filled with tragedy in our country’s classrooms as we reflect on the school violence that took place and the lives that were lost. The days, weeks and months following each tragic event often included strong words and swift action by federal and local officials. Proposed solutions have included such things as; increasing the presence of school police and security, arming teachers and staff, increasing surveillance and also implementing some tougher disciplinary practices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will School Safety Politics Affect Young Voter Turnout?</title>
      <link>/blog/voting-school-safety-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/voting-school-safety-politics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Young voters in America have historically shown a low percentage of voting participation, but this year… school safety politics might change that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the last 20 years, no more than 20 percent of those age 18 to 24 have gone to the polls to voice their opinions during a midterm election. This year could be different.. according to an Education Week study which surveyed the youngest eligible voters, nearly two-thirds of respondents said they plan to vote this year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovative Technology in Hospital Security</title>
      <link>/blog/funding-helps-stop-school-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/funding-helps-stop-school-violence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The US Department of Justice recently announced that more than $70 million in grant funding will go to over 220 jurisdictions across the country through the STOP School Violence Act. The money will provide support for school security, student and faculty training, and to aid law enforcement officers and first responders during incidents of school violence. The funding can also support new or existing crisis intervention teams.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The DOJ will also invest $1 million toward research on the factors that lead to mass shootings. Less than a week prior to this announcement, Attorney General Jeff Sessions announced $200,000 in funding for the National Association of School Resource Officers, which will help the organization expand and train more personnel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Plan to Mobilize School Safety Agents in NYC</title>
      <link>/blog/school-safety-agents/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/school-safety-agents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to New York City Mayor Bill de Blasio, last week was the start of a pilot program at multiple Bronx schools that will turn school safety agents into unarmed beat cops, roaming the halls and tasked with looking for wandering students, conversing with the students, identifying suspicious activity, and meeting with principals to discuss potential conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The point of all this is to try and mobilize the city’s school safety agents who currently stand or sit idly at entrances while requesting ID from visitors. Also, it’s an attempt to help cultivate active relationships between the safety officers and their community of students, teachers, parents and staff. Just the notion of having a school safety agent that students can feel comfortable speaking to on a daily basis can go a long way in helping to diffuse situations of distress and anxiety… and if nothing else, will hopefully work as a safety valve to relieve pressure from those in need.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tennessee Gives School Security Funding Statewide</title>
      <link>/blog/school-security-funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/school-security-funding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;State-wide safety reviews of nearly every public school in the state of Tennessee were recently conducted and completed for the first time ever. This comes after Tennessee Governor Bill Haslam announced the plans in March. As a result of the reviews being completed, Tennessee will be handing out unprecedented school security funding across the state.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The reviews were suggested by the School Safety Working Group established by Governor Haslam after the February Parkland, FL school shooting that killed 17 and injured 17 more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Federal Commission on School Safety Meets</title>
      <link>/blog/federal-commission-on-school-safety-meets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/federal-commission-on-school-safety-meets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Federal Commission on School Safety met Thursday, June 21st in Washington D.C. This is the second meeting of the school safety commission, which was created by President Trump in March of 2018 after the deadly Parkland, FL school shooting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Commission, which is led by U.S. Secretary of Education Betsy DeVos, chose to focus on the link between media and school violence. Controversy was started when, on Tuesday, Chairperson DeVos indicated that the commission on school safety will not be investigating the role that guns play in these incidents. Her statement, made in response to a question posed by Democratic Senator Patrick Leahy during a subcommittee hearing, bothered several groups who have taken the lead on the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
