<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Safety on 911Cellular</title>
    <link>/tag/safety/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Safety on 911Cellular</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tag/safety/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Safety Solutions for Cities</title>
      <link>/blog/safety-solutions-for-cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/safety-solutions-for-cities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are so many safety solutions for cities that are not always well known to the public, and we’d like to help share some information to keep you safe in your hometown.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Keeping a city safe is like building a house. It needs to start with a good foundation, then it requires a lot of work and the proper tools. You can’t build a house with just a hammer, no matter how good that hammer is. We offer tools that assist police departments and citizens. Safety solutions for cities can come in the form of app systems like ours, where we offer a security system in your pocket. 911Cellular offers &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/app-systems/&#34;&gt;PublicShield&lt;/a&gt;, which gives you the ability to receive mass notifications from city officials, gives you direct access to police with an app that can send out your exact location to emergency personnel in case of an emergency, and gives you the ability to share tips or suspicious activity (along with pictures or video) anonymously to your police department.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>911Cellular is named one of the Top Government Tech Solution Providers of 2018</title>
      <link>/blog/911cellular-is-named-one-of-the-top-government-tech-solution-providers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/911cellular-is-named-one-of-the-top-government-tech-solution-providers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;911Cellular is named one of the Top Government Tech Solution Providers of 2018 in CIO Applications Magazine. CIO Magazine sat down with Chad Salahshour, the President and CEO of 911Cellular, to talk about how 911Cellular came to fruition. Chad is still actively involved with a local police department, and it’s because of his law enforcement background that he created and started implementing our lifesaving technology across the country. 911Cellular works with dispatchers and smartphone users to open up the lines of emergency communication and to pinpoint your location during an emergency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Guide to Holiday Safety</title>
      <link>/blog/holiday-safety-tips-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/holiday-safety-tips-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The holidays are always fun. Shopping for gifts for your loved ones, finding great deals online, and going on holiday vacations are just a few of the things that most of us look forward to. But unfortunately, holidays are also a time where holiday safety issues arise, but we very rarely do we think about holiday safety and it’s importance. So we wanted to give you holiday safety tips that you can use to safeguard yourself, your home, and your loved ones. These holiday safety tips are things that you can practice all of the time; not just during the holidays.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
