<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Holiday Safety on 911Cellular</title>
    <link>/tag/holiday-safety/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Holiday Safety on 911Cellular</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tag/holiday-safety/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Staying Safe on NYE</title>
      <link>/blog/staying-safe-on-nye/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/staying-safe-on-nye/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NYE can be such a fun holiday, but it’s important to stay safely enjoy the night. New Year’s Eve sees the highest percentage of deaths related to alcohol. Almost half of all car accidents on NYE and New Year’s Day are due to drinking and driving.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t yet, please download Uber or Lyft and familiarize yourself with the apps. You can also save a cab company’s phone number in your phone. But if you’re planning on drinking, don’t plan on driving. A $30 Uber ride is much cheaper than a DUI or worse… Do NOT drink and drive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Guide to Holiday Safety</title>
      <link>/blog/holiday-safety-tips-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/holiday-safety-tips-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The holidays are always fun. Shopping for gifts for your loved ones, finding great deals online, and going on holiday vacations are just a few of the things that most of us look forward to. But unfortunately, holidays are also a time where holiday safety issues arise, but we very rarely do we think about holiday safety and it’s importance. So we wanted to give you holiday safety tips that you can use to safeguard yourself, your home, and your loved ones. These holiday safety tips are things that you can practice all of the time; not just during the holidays.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
