<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home Healthcare on 911Cellular</title>
    <link>https://911cellular.com/tag/home-healthcare/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home Healthcare on 911Cellular</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://911cellular.com/tag/home-healthcare/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Connecticut Addresses Home Health Care Workers&#39; Safety with Public Act 24-19</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/connecticut-home-health-care-workers-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/connecticut-home-health-care-workers-safety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This past May, the Connecticut state legislature and Governor Ned Lamont took the first steps towards addressing unsafe work environments for healthcare workers through &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cga.ct.gov/asp/cgabillstatus/cgabillstatus.asp?selBillType=Public&amp;#43;Act&amp;amp;which_year=2024&amp;amp;bill_num=19&#34;&gt;Public Act 24-19&lt;/a&gt;, also known as An Act Concerning the Health and Safety of Connecticut Residents. The legislation focuses on improving the health and safety of Connecticut&amp;rsquo;s vulnerable and underserved populations as well as the home health care workers who serve them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Creating the In-Home Safety Grant Program was vital to addressing concerns about increased violence against home health care workers. The program provides funds to home health providers for improved safety protocols.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preventing Workplace Violence in Healthcare: Safety Measures for Healthcare Workers</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/preventing-workplace-violence-in-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/preventing-workplace-violence-in-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how healthcare workers can protect themselves from workplace violence with these safety measures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Predicament for Home Healthcare Workers: Uncontrolled Environments</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/home-healthcare-workers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/home-healthcare-workers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As baby boomers age, the need for nurses and home healthcare workers will continue to climb. The Census bureau expects the number of people &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.census.gov/prod/2014pubs/p25-1140.pdf&#34;&gt;over the age of 65 to nearly double from 2012 to 2050&lt;/a&gt;. In addition to a large aging population, more people are preferring to receive medical treatment and end of life care at home, as opposed to assisted living centers or hospitals. According to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aarp.org/research/topics/community/info-2014/home-community-services-10.html&#34;&gt;2010 AARP survey&lt;/a&gt; nearly 75% of respondents (all age 45+) strongly agreed with the statement, “what I’d really like to do is stay in my current residence for as long as possible”. With more individuals falling in the 65+ age bracket and requesting healthcare at home the demand for nurses and home healthcare workers is skyrocketing. In fact, the demand for home healthcare workers is slated to increase by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bls.gov/ooh/healthcare/home-health-aides-and-personal-care-aides.htm&#34;&gt;36% between 2018 and 2028&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
