<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computer Panic Buttons on 911Cellular</title>
    <link>/tag/computer-panic-buttons/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computer Panic Buttons on 911Cellular</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tag/computer-panic-buttons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Duress Buttons Are a Proven Security Measure For All Institutions</title>
      <link>/blog/duress-buttons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/duress-buttons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore the importance of duress buttons as a security measure in various institutions and their effectiveness in reducing violent incidents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Panic Button Guide for Staff Members</title>
      <link>/blog/panic-button/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/panic-button/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover how panic buttons can enhance safety and security in the workplace with this comprehensive guide for staff members.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The next generation emergency response team is not what you think</title>
      <link>/blog/emergency-response-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/emergency-response-teams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A little while back we touched on the importance of emergency action planning and how every organization should have an emergency response plan (EAP) in place even if they are not required to do so. For every organization, an EAP is only as good as the people who can coordinate the response and carry out the plan in place. In most cases, these people are labelled as the emergency response team (ERT) members and are relied upon to deliver swift, calculated response during times of crisis (when others are often frantic).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As is always the case for emergency response, each organization’s plan is unique, and some institutions are required to have more thorough planning in place than others. That being said, there are guidelines and insights that can apply to all organizations as it regards to emergency response teams and how to make them more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) suggests that ERT members should be &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.osha.gov/sites/default/files/publications/factsheet-workplaceevergencies.pdf&#34;&gt;well trained in emergency response&lt;/a&gt;, know the organization’s specific emergency plan, and be physically capable of carrying out the proper emergency response duties assigned to them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workplace violence prevention: 5 things to do today</title>
      <link>/blog/workplace-violence-prevention/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/workplace-violence-prevention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Workplace violence has become a major issue for many businesses and healthcare systems in the U.S. for decades. According to the Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA), almost 2 million U.S. workers report having been a victim of violence at work each year. This number is even more staggering when you consider that about 3 out of every 4 workplace violence incidents occur in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/industries/healthcare/&#34;&gt;healthcare&lt;/a&gt; or social services industries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to the Bureau of Labor Statistics, 20,790 workers in the private industry &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/niosh/topics/violence/fastfacts.html&#34;&gt;experienced trauma&lt;/a&gt; from nonfatal workplace violence in 2018. Of these workers, over 70% were female and 20% required a month or longer away from work to recover.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These jarring statistics should alone provide enough motivation for employers to commit to a non-violent workplace environment, but the data even shows that there are significant financial consequences of persistent workplace violence as well. In healthcare for instance, over 58 incidents occur annually per 10,000 workers with an average cost per incident of over $3,000. This means that annually, per 10,000 workers, healthcare systems are losing nearly $200,000.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Despite all this negativity, there are many things that your organization can do today to help prevent workplace violence incidents from occurring regularly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature Focus: System Wide Multilingual Support</title>
      <link>/blog/multilingual-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/multilingual-support/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week’s Feature Focus, where we highlight a specific aspect of the 911Cellular Solution and find out what makes it so valuable. Today’s topic is multilingual support and the entirety of its reach through various products and services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is offering multilingual support so important?&lt;/strong&gt; According to the United States Census Bureau, there are over 350 languages spoken within the United States. The graph below shows the number of languages spoken based on major metropolitan areas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wireless Panic Button Solutions Crucial For Emergency Departments</title>
      <link>/blog/wireless-panic-button/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/wireless-panic-button/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is a complete wireless panic button solution? Why is it important for hospitals and particularly emergency departments to have one?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s not a secret to those who work in the healthcare industry that violence against employees is a major concern. And according to many, that violence is even more prevalent within emergency room departments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a recent survey conducted by ACEP (American College of Emergency Physicians), nearly half (47%) of emergency physicians report being physically assaulted at some point during their career. And almost 70% of emergency physicians say that emergency department violence has increased in the last half decade.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The importance of workplace panic button implementation</title>
      <link>/blog/workplace-panic-buttons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/workplace-panic-buttons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Workplace panic button implementations are a vital security measure that every enterprise should deploy, but with more affordable software technologies being developed, even small businesses are beginning to benefit from these crucial, life-saving solutions. Workplaces often take various measures in order to ensure that their employees feel safe in their working environment. This is helpful in boosting their productivity and makes them feel more relaxed, but it also can reduce the liability of an organization based on the reduced severity and quantity of incidents that tend to occur after workplace panic button implementation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
