<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>“Hospital Safety” on 911Cellular</title>
    <link>https://911cellular.com/tag/hospital-safety/</link>
    <description>Recent content in “Hospital Safety” on 911Cellular</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://911cellular.com/tag/hospital-safety/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tools to Help Maintain Hospital Operations During Severe Winter Weather</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/tools-to-help-maintain-hospital-operations-during-severe-winter-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/tools-to-help-maintain-hospital-operations-during-severe-winter-weather/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When severe winter weather strikes, hospitals face unique challenges that can disrupt critical operations. From icy roads delaying staff commutes to power outages affecting life-saving equipment, the stakes are high. An effective emergency notification system and safety app can make the difference between chaos and continuity. Here’s how these technologies can enhance employee safety and keep hospitals running smoothly when winter weather hits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective De-Escalation Strategies for Healthcare Workers: Maintaining Calm and Safety</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/effective-de-escalation-strategies-for-healthcare-workers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/effective-de-escalation-strategies-for-healthcare-workers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Effective de-escalation strategies in healthcare settings are vital for ensuring patients&amp;rsquo; and staff&amp;rsquo;s safety and well-being. Tensions can arise quickly due to factors such as a patient&amp;rsquo;s anxiety, cognitive impairments or external stressors. De-escalation strategies provide healthcare professionals with the tools to manage these high-pressure situations and diffuse potentially volatile encounters with empathy and skill. Below, we will outline proven techniques that can help de-escalate tense situations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
