<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chimé Richardson on 911Cellular</title>
    <link>https://911cellular.com/author/chim%C3%A9-richardson/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chimé Richardson on 911Cellular</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://911cellular.com/author/chim%C3%A9-richardson/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Can Businesses Reopen Safely?</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/reopen-safely/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/reopen-safely/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While still in the midst of the COVID-19 pandemic many organizations are already turning their thoughts, and worries, to an unclear future. How do we collectively restart a stalled economy? What steps will it take for businesses, community organizations, universities, etc. to reopen safely? Reopening processes will need to be different for each organization and is dependent on several factors …&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt; and the subsequent &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.multistate.us/pages/covid-19-policy-tracker&#34;&gt;rules and regulations put in place by each state&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Availability of resources&lt;/strong&gt; such as masks, gloves, testing kits, etc. Access to PPE will continue to be necessary to safeguard community members and prevent a resurgence of COVID-19 cases.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infection rate.&lt;/strong&gt; Knowing the number of COVID-19 cases within your organization is just as important as knowing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/index.html&#34;&gt;number of cases in surrounding areas and states&lt;/a&gt; (i.e infection potentiality).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No matter how each of these variables affect your organization, one thing is clear, emerging from this pandemic will take collaboration and clear communication on both an organizational and individual level to reopen safely. On an organizational level this means communicating protocol changes on a consistent basis. This will require that you stay abreast of evolving current state rules/guidelines and how they apply specifically to your organization. Synthesizing this information and providing it in an easily digestible and applicable way is key to solidifying adherence. Communicating protocol changes needs to occur over a wide range of communication platforms in order to reach all members of your audience. However, communicating to your audience is not enough. Collecting community feedback is an essential component to understanding and addressing community needs. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/products/emergency-notification-system/&#34;&gt;911Cellular’s Mass Notification System&lt;/a&gt; allows organizations to send out mass notifications via 10 different platforms (call, text, email, etc.). Organizations can also choose to include community survey questions and feedback boards with their with mass notifications. This makes it effortless to collect and understand community feedback.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature Focus: COVID Tools, Submit Tip &amp; Resource Tile</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/covid-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/covid-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week’s Feature Focus, where we highlight a specific aspect of the 911Cellular Solution and find out what makes it so valuable. Today’s topic is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/products/mobile-safety-app/&#34;&gt;Mobile Safety App&lt;/a&gt; features that can assist your organization in reopening, remaining open safely, and preventing the spread of COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://911cellular.com/images/blog/911Cellular-Submit-Tip-COVID-Feature.jpg.webp&#34; alt=&#34;=Covid safety app&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Submit Tip feature&lt;/strong&gt; shines for its ability to be customized and molded to fit your organization’s needs. Administrators can create tip categories such as ‘social distancing violation’, ‘unsafe public gathering’, etc. App users can easily and discreetly notify health and safety forces anonymously as well as include helpful pictures and videos. In turn, safety forces have the option to start a conversation with the tip submitter, even if the tip submitter chose to remain anonymous. Additionally, the organization’s Administrators can be proactive in encouraging use of the feature by enabling a ‘See Something, Say Something’ campaign. This campaign will automatically send push notifications to a small portion of your community each day, asking them a question such as ‘have you seen any mask violations lately?’. When an app user clicks into the push notification, they will be taken directly to the Submit Tip feature.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Becoming Alyssa’s Law Compliant 101</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/alyssas-law-compliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/alyssas-law-compliance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On February 14, 2018, a gunman opened fire at Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School in Parkland, Florida, killing 17 people. One of the victims of this horrific tragedy was Alyssa Alhadeff, a 14 year old talented writer and soccer player. In the wake of her daughter’s death, Lori Alhadeff, Alyssa’s mother, took action to prevent future school violence. This is how Alyssa’s law was created.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Alyssa’s  Law?&lt;/strong&gt; Alyssa’s Law is critical legislation which addresses law enforcement response time when a life-threatening emergency occurs. The law calls for the installation of silent panic alarms that are directly linked to law enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The COVID Safety System provides much-needed clarity for your organization</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/covid-safety-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/covid-safety-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The rhythm of our daily life, the decisions we make, and how we operate our organizations have all been deeply affected by the COVID-19 pandemic. For many organizations, the pressure to reopen for economic and social reasons are being heavily weighed against exposure and liability risks. Business owners find themselves with decision paralysis when it comes to determining what a successful and safe reopening process looks like. In order to cut through the confusion and frustration surrounding reopening, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/&#34;&gt;911Cellular&lt;/a&gt; has created the COVID Safety System. If you’re thinking about reopening your facilities, do so safely by reducing the level of uncertainty involving COVID-19 within your organization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bolstering your existing blue light towers</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/blue-light-towers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/blue-light-towers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Blue light towers have been the unrelenting security guards of universities, hospitals, and parks far and wide for decades. The highly recognizable tall, thin, blue towers are a symbol of safety… something to run to if things go wrong during an early morning jog or a late night walk home. The towers provide a way for people to communicate directly with nearby security forces. Some blue lights provide 2-way communication with a dispatch center, while others provide a panic button feature. Due to the prevalence of blue light towers, anyone (at any time) can easily alert security forces that they’re in distress as long as there is a blue light tower in that area.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature Focus: Blue Light Tower System Integration</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/blue-light-tower-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/blue-light-tower-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week’s Feature Focus, where we highlight a specific aspect of the 911Cellular Solution and find out what makes it so valuable. Today we’re focusing on integrating 911Cellular software into your existing blue light tower system.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An easily identifiable symbol of safety, blue light towers can be seen across universities, hospitals, and public spaces nationwide. The premise of the blue light tower is simple, to provide an easy way for the public to notify safety forces in the event of an emergency. Blue light towers remove the need to remember an emergency phone number, dial a phone, or locate a nearby safety officer. Activations made through a blue light tower are typically routed back to an organization’s dispatch center in the form of a phone call or pager notification.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote Deployment During a Pandemic</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/remote-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/remote-deployment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic has emphasized the importance of contactless delivery when it comes to grocery shopping and food delivery. But what about businesses outside of the food industry? How can businesses owners, integrators and other partners sell their products while the majority of people are still working away from the office?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many Americans are still staying home, even as some states begin to reopen, according to an analysis from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/2020/national/map-us-still-staying-home-coronavirus/?itid=hp_hp-banner-main_graphic-stayathome-1140am:homepage/story-ans&#34;&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature Focus: System Wide Multilingual Support</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/multilingual-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/multilingual-support/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week’s Feature Focus, where we highlight a specific aspect of the 911Cellular Solution and find out what makes it so valuable. Today’s topic is multilingual support and the entirety of its reach through various products and services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is offering multilingual support so important?&lt;/strong&gt; According to the United States Census Bureau, there are over 350 languages spoken within the United States. The graph below shows the number of languages spoken based on major metropolitan areas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Predicament for Home Healthcare Workers: Uncontrolled Environments</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/home-healthcare-workers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/home-healthcare-workers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As baby boomers age, the need for nurses and home healthcare workers will continue to climb. The Census bureau expects the number of people &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.census.gov/prod/2014pubs/p25-1140.pdf&#34;&gt;over the age of 65 to nearly double from 2012 to 2050&lt;/a&gt;. In addition to a large aging population, more people are preferring to receive medical treatment and end of life care at home, as opposed to assisted living centers or hospitals. According to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aarp.org/research/topics/community/info-2014/home-community-services-10.html&#34;&gt;2010 AARP survey&lt;/a&gt; nearly 75% of respondents (all age 45+) strongly agreed with the statement, “what I’d really like to do is stay in my current residence for as long as possible”. With more individuals falling in the 65+ age bracket and requesting healthcare at home the demand for nurses and home healthcare workers is skyrocketing. In fact, the demand for home healthcare workers is slated to increase by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bls.gov/ooh/healthcare/home-health-aides-and-personal-care-aides.htm&#34;&gt;36% between 2018 and 2028&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 things your organization should do to prepare for the upcoming climate crisis</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/preempt-emergencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/preempt-emergencies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No organization can fully prepare for every possible scenario, but there are ways to preempt emergencies that can help every organization, regardless of size. Communication remains a key piece to emergency management and preparedness, so we’ve outlined a few ways to get ahead of the curve when it comes to protecting your organization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Addressing Community Pandemic Related Stress</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/pandemic-related-stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/pandemic-related-stress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COVID-19 has presented everyone with a multitude of internal and external pandemic related stress points to grapple with. For some, it’s panic over the loss of a job, depression spawned from extended social isolation, or exhaustion fueled by never ending anxiety. While Netflix, Instagram and other platforms can provide much needed temporary distractions, they both fall short in addressing the root problem. Below are two common stressors that members of your community may be experiencing and some ways that you can help out:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Healthcare heroes are getting assaulted and it&#39;s costing millions</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/violence-against-healthcare-workers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/violence-against-healthcare-workers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2020 the public is visiting hospitals and emergency departments more than ever. An unfortunate parallel increase can be seen in cases of violence against healthcare workers. What are the immediate and long term costs of workplace violence on healthcare organizations? And more importantly,  what can be done to minimize these costs and protect healthcare workers against the steady rise in workplace violence?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Calls are Overwhelming 911 Dispatch Centers</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/covid-19-calls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/covid-19-calls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The number of cases of COVID-19 continue to rise, shelter in place ordinances have rolled out, and in some cases have been extended. Living within a pandemic has left many with questions and few reliable sources for answers. Many individuals have turned to calling 911 for answers to their questions about shelter in place orders and Coronavirus related information. Police departments and emergency dispatchers have become inundated with the severe uptick in COVID-19 calls.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Communicating COVID-19 Protocol to Healthcare Workers</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/covid-19-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/covid-19-protocol/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices for Crisis Communication: Pandemic Communication Outreach</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/pandemic-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/pandemic-communication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The rise and spread of COVID-19 has communities, businesses, and medical facilities scrambling to effectively communicate crucial information within their organizations, and to wider audiences such as patients, students, customers, etc. For many organizations this is the first time they’ve had to implement pandemic communication and mass notification practices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To assist organizations grappling with how to effectively communicate with their community in the midst of the COVID-19 pandemic, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/&#34;&gt;911Cellular&lt;/a&gt; has developed three best practices for effective pandemic communication…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coronavirus Preparedness for Hospitals and Medical Providers Focus: Multilevel Effective Communication Practices</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/coronavirus-preparedness-for-hospitals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/coronavirus-preparedness-for-hospitals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Centers for Disease Control (CDC) released a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/downloads/hospital-preparedness-checklist.pdf&#34;&gt;Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Hospital Preparedness Assessment Tool&lt;/a&gt;. The document outlines six best practices in regards to Coronavirus preparedness for hospitals and medical centers. Hospitals are not required or mandated to follow these six practices. However, they are strongly advised to review and apply them in preparation for potential arrivals of COVID-19 patients. The six best practices for Coronavirus preparedness for hospitals include…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mental Toll of School Shootings</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/mental-toll-of-school-shootings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/mental-toll-of-school-shootings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recent news of a shooting in El Paso shows that mass shootings and gun violence still remain a problem in America. The youngest victim was 15 years old, a sophomore in high school.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While news of mass shootings are abhorrent, they’re especially heartbreaking when they occur in schools. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.911cellular.com/school-shooting-lessons-learned/&#34;&gt;The incident at Noblesville West Middle School shows that school shootings are traumatic&lt;/a&gt; regardless of how many casualties there are. Schools are meant to be safe spaces for our children to learn and grow as individuals. It doesn’t make sense for us to bid them goodbye every morning knowing that their safety isn’t a given.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thus, school shootings affect the entire community, but this is especially true for the children. Living through a traumatic experience isn’t easy, which means teachers and parents are left struggling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
