<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>911Cellular</title>
    <link>https://911cellular.com/tag/911cellular/</link>
    <description>Recent content on 911Cellular</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://911cellular.com/tag/911cellular/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spark Alert Relay: Revolutionizing School Safety with Automation</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/spark-alert-relay-school-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/spark-alert-relay-school-safety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Schools face unique safety challenges that require rapid, coordinated responses to mitigate harm to students and staff. With 911Cellular&amp;rsquo;s newest innovation, Spark Alert Relay, schools can automate critical safety responses that traditionally required manual intervention. With Spark, physical security measures like alarms, PA announcements and building lockdowns can be immediately activated upon receiving a panic signal, significantly reducing response time during an emergency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Staying Connected When It Matters Most</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/staying-connected-when-it-matters-most/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/staying-connected-when-it-matters-most/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At 911Cellular, we&amp;rsquo;ve always believed that strong connections are the foundation of safe communities. From our earliest days, we&amp;rsquo;ve been committed to building solutions that bridge the gap between people in need and first responders. Today, our new overview video highlights that mission—reinforcing the importance of connection, especially in moments of crisis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;video controls=&#34;&#34; preload=&#34;metadata&#34; poster=&#39;/images/home-v2/720p-thumbnail-911cellular-brand-overview-video-2024 copy.webp&#39; &gt;&#xD;&#xA;                    &lt;source type=&#34;video/mp4&#34; src=&#34;https://911cellular-bucket.s3.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/911Cellular+Brand+-+Overview+Video+-+2024.mp4&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;/video&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our journey has been one of growth and innovation. We&amp;rsquo;ve consistently expanded our products and product functionality to meet the diverse safety needs of &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/industries/k12schools/&#34;&gt;K-12 schools&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/industries/higher-education/&#34;&gt;college campuses&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/industries/healthcare/&#34;&gt;hospitals&lt;/a&gt; and businesses. We understand that today&amp;rsquo;s institutions face unprecedented challenges both in their physical and digital spaces. That&amp;rsquo;s why we&amp;rsquo;re committed to staying at the forefront of technology, offering mobile &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/products/mobile-safety-app/&#34;&gt;safety apps&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/products/wearable-panic-buttons/&#34;&gt;panic buttons&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://911cellular.com/products/emergency-notification-system/&#34;&gt;critical incident management software&lt;/a&gt; that help schools and businesses protect their people, comply with regulations and respond quickly and discreetly in crucial moments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winter Safety Tips: Stay Warm and Safe</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/winter-safety-tips-stay-warm-and-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/winter-safety-tips-stay-warm-and-safe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover essential winter safety tips to stay warm and safe in extremely cold weather.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Celebrate New Year Safely: A Guide</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/how-to-celebrate-new-year-safely-a-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/how-to-celebrate-new-year-safely-a-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover essential tips and guidelines to ensure a safe and enjoyable New Year&amp;rsquo;s celebration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protesters Focus on Effort to Occupy University Police Offices</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/protesters-occupy-university-police/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/protesters-occupy-university-police/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly 3 months ago, Jason Washington, a 45 year old Navy veteran, was shot and killed by Portland State University police officers after being told by police to drop his friend’s gun during a street fight. Jason was trying to de-escalate the fight, according to witnesses and body cam footage, that started when his friend, Jeremy Wilkinson, used a racial slur and threw a stranger’s phone.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On Monday, students and protesters made demands as their rallies turned into an effort to occupy university police offices. Protesters say they will occupy the space until their demands are met: the immediate disarmament of PSU police officers, the firing of the officers involved in the case, and a permanent memorial to Jason Washington erected on campus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hospitals aren&#39;t safe places for these individuals</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/hospital-safety-and-eliminating-workplace-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/hospital-safety-and-eliminating-workplace-violence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hospital safety isn’t something the average person thinks about. Hospitals are where we go for emergencies, surgeries, births, and general ailments. As a patient of hospitals, we think of the staff as our care providers. What most people don’t know is that between 2011 and 2013, nearly 75% of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fiercehealthcare.com/healthcare/workplace-violence-healthcare-underreported-and-often-ignored&#34;&gt;workplace assaults&lt;/a&gt; took place in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fiercehealthcare.com/finance/violence-cost-hospitals-2-7b-2016-aha-report-finds&#34;&gt;healthcare settings&lt;/a&gt;. While we are getting treated for our health issues, the staff in our hospitals are getting assaulted by their patients or the patient’s family members/friends. This is a very serious issue, and one that we don’t hear about often enough.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>911Cellular is named one of the Top Government Tech Solution Providers of 2018</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/911cellular-is-named-one-of-the-top-government-tech-solution-providers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/911cellular-is-named-one-of-the-top-government-tech-solution-providers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;911Cellular is named one of the Top Government Tech Solution Providers of 2018 in CIO Applications Magazine. CIO Magazine sat down with Chad Salahshour, the President and CEO of 911Cellular, to talk about how 911Cellular came to fruition. Chad is still actively involved with a local police department, and it’s because of his law enforcement background that he created and started implementing our lifesaving technology across the country. 911Cellular works with dispatchers and smartphone users to open up the lines of emergency communication and to pinpoint your location during an emergency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>School Shootings: Can we prevent them?</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/school-shootings-can-we-prevent-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/school-shootings-can-we-prevent-them/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;School shootings are becoming increasingly more common, and we find ourselves asking “Can we stop school shootings from happening?”  There is no way to ensure school shooting prevention, but we would like to share some information that may be useful when it comes to creating a school and home environment that may be beneficial to putting an end to some of the violence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Strength-based support. This is a phrase you may have seen before, and we’ll explain exactly what it means. All too often, active school shooters feel alienated and alone. They feel like outcasts. If you can identify a student that is having a hard time in mainstream classes, but may have great artistic ability or they really enjoy coding in computer class, you can offer them strength-based support. Find those kids and offer them incentives to strengthen their areas of expertise. Corrective teaching is great for most students; helping them identify their weaknesses and working to correct those issues. But children who suffer tremendous isolation will only feel MORE isolated in that type of learning environment. By nurturing students that feel like they’re outcasts, we may be able to prevent school shootings.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Schools can offer guidance from a Relationship Officer. These can be guidance counselors, teachers, or other facility members that offer support to students who’s home lives may not have strong adult role models. Schools can also employ a Relationship Officer. These are different from counselors. Their goals are to connect with students and offer them a healthy adult/student relationship that will open the doors to trust and acceptance.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you see something, report it. Whether it’s bullying, signs of abuse, signs of malnourishment, or anything that’s way outside the norm. Most active school shooters acted violently because of extreme bullying or deep feelings of isolation. We can prevent school shootings by making sure all students feel cared for. A lot of schools are overwhelmed and it’s hard to report every single incident, but it’s the one way to ensure that everything is being documented and if there are enough incidents with one student, you will be able to determine that there is a pattern. Counties are also juggling more work than most can handle, but creating a paper trail WILL help in the long run. Even if you’re the only one that sees the paper trail, at least you’ll be able to easily identify a student that could be a risk or at risk.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Talk to your children about mental health, and let them know that there is no stigma involved with needed to talk to someone. We would much rather see a large influx of children talking to therapists as opposed to children shooting up schools. If you think your own child may need help, there is no shame in getting them into therapy. You haven’t failed as a parent; you are actually doing them a favor by getting them the help they need. We know you would rather see your child get help and potentially stop them from becoming an active school shooter. Most counties and cities even offer free services.  Children Services would much rather help you get the resources you need instead of taking a child from your home or worse, putting your child into a detention center. Do not be afraid to contact Children Services or your child’s school if you feel there are psychological issues. You might be surprised to learn that Children Services also offers support groups for parents, and you as a parent may benefit from them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Keeping our children safe should be our number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Staying Safe on NYE</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/staying-safe-on-nye/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/staying-safe-on-nye/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NYE can be such a fun holiday, but it’s important to stay safely enjoy the night. New Year’s Eve sees the highest percentage of deaths related to alcohol. Almost half of all car accidents on NYE and New Year’s Day are due to drinking and driving.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t yet, please download Uber or Lyft and familiarize yourself with the apps. You can also save a cab company’s phone number in your phone. But if you’re planning on drinking, don’t plan on driving. A $30 Uber ride is much cheaper than a DUI or worse… Do NOT drink and drive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Guide to Holiday Safety</title>
      <link>https://911cellular.com/blog/holiday-safety-tips-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://911cellular.com/blog/holiday-safety-tips-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The holidays are always fun. Shopping for gifts for your loved ones, finding great deals online, and going on holiday vacations are just a few of the things that most of us look forward to. But unfortunately, holidays are also a time where holiday safety issues arise, but we very rarely do we think about holiday safety and it’s importance. So we wanted to give you holiday safety tips that you can use to safeguard yourself, your home, and your loved ones. These holiday safety tips are things that you can practice all of the time; not just during the holidays.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
